<?xml version="1.0" encoding="latin-1"?><sentences><sentence date="20150106" id="1837952" ><text>W
U.S.  veteran and airline pilot Christopher V. Hill of New Hampshire took some time to talk with Wikinews about his campaign for the U.S. Republican Party's 2016 presidential nomination.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (NP (NP (NNP U.S.) (NN veteran) (CC and) (NN airline) (NN pilot) (NNP Christopher) (NNP V.) (NNP Hill)) (PP (IN of) (NP (NNP New) (NNP Hampshire)))) (VP (VBD took) (NP (NP (DT some) (NN time)) (SBAR (S (VP (TO to) (VP (VB talk) (PP (IN with) (NP (NNP Wikinews))) (PP (IN about) (NP (NP (PRP$ his) (NN campaign)) (PP (IN for) (NP (NP (DT the) (NNP U.S.) (NNP Republican) (NNP Party) (POS 's)) (CD 2016) (JJ presidential) (NN nomination))))))))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150105" id="1838502" ><text>F
, the self-described "most censored director in France", died yesterday aged 86. ]] Vautier focused on French colonies. He made over 150 films and targeted what he described as "lack of teachers and doctors, the crimes committed by the French Army in the name of France, the instrumentalization of the colonized peoples". One topic of particular focus was the war in Algeria. Between 1954 and 1962 Algerians fought for, and won, their independence from France.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (NP (, ,) (NP (NP (NP (DT the) (JJ self-described) (`` ``) (RBS most) (VBN censored) (NN director)) (PP (IN in) (NP (NNP France)))) ('' '') (, ,) (S (VP (VBD died) (NP (NP (NN yesterday)) (ADJP (JJ aged) (NP (CD 86))))) (. .) (-RRB- -RSB-) (-RRB- -RSB-)))))</parse><sentence date="20150107" id="1842757" ><text>F
An explosion that took place in a barber shop next door to the Colorado Springs, Colorado office of the National Association for the Advancement of Colored People (NAACP) yesterday is currently being investigated by the FBI's , as well as the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms and Explosives. Officials said the explosive device was placed next to a can of gasoline but the gasoline did not ignite after the device detonated.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (NP (NP (DT An) (NN explosion)) (SBAR (WHNP (WDT that)) (S (VP (VBD took) (NP (NN place)) (PP (IN in) (NP (NP (NP (DT a) (NN barber) (NN shop)) (NP (JJ next) (NN door))) (PP (TO to) (NP (DT the) (NNP Colorado) (NNP Springs)))))))) (, ,) (NP (NP (NP (NNP Colorado) (NN office)) (PP (IN of) (NP (DT the) (NNP National) (NNP Association)))) (PP (IN for) (NP (NP (DT the) (NNP Advancement)) (PP (IN of) (NP (NP (NNP Colored) (NNS People)) (PRN (-LRB- -LRB-) (NP (NNP NAACP)) (-RRB- -RRB-))))))) (NP (NN yesterday))) (VP (VBZ is) (ADVP (RB currently)) (VP (VBG being) (VP (VBN investigated) (PP (IN by) (NP (NP (DT the) (NNP FBI) (POS 's)) (, ,) (CONJP (RB as) (RB well) (IN as)) (NP (NP (DT the) (NNP Bureau)) (PP (IN of) (NP (NNP Alcohol) (, ,) (NN Tobacco) (, ,) (NNS Firearms) (CC and) (NNS Explosives))))))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150108" id="1843528" ><text>J
Representative  was re-elected as Speaker of the   on Tuesday despite a right-wing rebellion of 25 members. Boehner's appointment as Speaker passed with 216 of the 408 votes.  Senator  was also sworn in on Tuesday as the  majority leader, marking the first time in eight years when Republicans have controlled both the House and Senate.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (NP (NNP Representative)) (VP (VBD was) (VP (VBN re-elected) (PP (IN as) (NP (NP (NNP Speaker)) (PP (IN of) (NP (DT the) (PP (IN on) (NP (NNP Tuesday))))))) (PP (IN despite) (NP (NP (DT a) (JJ right-wing) (NN rebellion)) (PP (IN of) (NP (CD 25) (NNS members))))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150110" id="1843534" ><text>R
]] On Wednesday,  and collaborators reported in the journal  on an unusual light signal they say suggests two supermassive black holes are merging, a phenomenon never seen before, though theorized.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (-RRB- -RSB-) (-RRB- -RSB-) (PP (IN On) (NP (NNP Wednesday))) (PRN (, ,) (CC and) (S (NP (NP (NNS collaborators)) (VP (VBN reported) (PP (IN in) (NP (DT the) (NN journal)))) (PP (IN on) (NP (NP (DT an) (JJ unusual) (JJ light) (NN signal)) (SBAR (S (NP (PRP they)) (VP (VBP say))))))) (VP (VBZ suggests) (SBAR (S (NP (CD two) (JJ supermassive) (JJ black) (NNS holes)) (VP (VBP are) (VP (VBG merging))))))) (, ,)) (NP (DT a) (NN phenomenon)) (ADVP (RB never)) (VP (VBN seen) (ADVP (IN before)) (, ,) (SBAR (IN though) (S (VP (VBN theorized))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150111" id="1849477" ><text>S
Space transport services company SpaceX launched their  to the International Space Station  yesterday. The spacecraft - containing more than 2,200 (5,000 ) of food, experiments, and spare parts - successfully decoupled from the launch rocket and should reach the station early tomorrow.  The launch was postponed from Tuesday because of a technical issue on the second stage of the rocket. The shipment includes replacements for cargo aboard the spaceship Cygnus, destroyed during a failed launch in October. Cygnus belonged to the rival .</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (NP (NP (NN Space) (NN transport) (NNS services) (NN company)) (NNP SpaceX)) (VP (VBD launched) (NP (PRP$ their) (PP (TO to) (NP (DT the) (NNP International) (NNP Space) (NNP Station)))) (NP (NN yesterday))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150112" id="1852403" ><text>M
Following the shootings at the offices of , millions of people turned out yesterday for marches in , in cities across , and around the world. Reported estimates of between 1.5 and 2 million people rallied in Paris, and the French interior ministry estimated 3.7 million or more rallied across France.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (PP (VBG Following) (NP (NP (DT the) (NNS shootings)) (PP (IN at) (NP (NP (DT the) (NNS offices)) (PP (IN of)))))) (, ,) (NP (NP (NNS millions)) (PP (IN of) (NP (NNS people)))) (VP (VBD turned) (PRT (RP out)) (NP (NN yesterday)) (PP (IN for) (NP (NP (NNS marches)) (SBAR (IN in) (PRN (, ,) (PP (IN in) (NP (NP (NNS cities)) (ADJP (IN across)))) (, ,)) (CC and) (PP (IN around) (NP (DT the) (NN world))))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150113" id="1853457" ><text>S
A Sheriff in Aberdeen yesterday jailed gamekeeper George Mutch for crimes against . It is believed to be the first time anybody has been imprisoned for  persecution in Scotland.  Mutch, 48, killed a protected , and used illegal traps to capture a  and a second goshawk. He was convicted last month  of four offences, which he committed in 2012 in .</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (NP (DT A) (NAC (NNP Sheriff) (PP (IN in) (NP (NNP Aberdeen)))) (NN yesterday)) (VP (VBN jailed) (NP (NN gamekeeper) (NNP George) (NNP Mutch)) (PP (IN for) (NP (NP (NNS crimes)) (PP (IN against))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150114" id="1855493" ><text>U
Tests yesterday proved negative for Ebola on the remains of a US soldier who died in Texas after deployment to Liberia. The 24-year-old had been monitoring potential symptoms of the disease. ] / Dr. Frederick Murphy] An initial screen was clear yesterday but a more conclusive test, mandated by the , was required. That also proved negative and state and national officials have been appraised.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (NP (NNS Tests)) (NP (NN yesterday)) (VP (VBD proved) (ADJP (JJ negative) (PP (IN for) (NP (NP (NNP Ebola)) (PP (IN on) (NP (NP (DT the) (NNS remains)) (PP (IN of) (NP (NP (DT a) (NNP US) (NN soldier)) (SBAR (WHNP (WP who)) (S (VP (VBD died) (PP (IN in) (NP (NNP Texas))) (PP (IN after) (NP (NP (NN deployment)) (PP (TO to) (NP (NNP Liberia)))))))))))))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150121" id="1865563" ><text>U
Thousands of Ukrainians in Kyiv took part on Sunday in marches in memory of reported victims of  militants in a tragedy on January 13 near  in Donetsk Oblast. On that day reportedly thirteen people on a bus were killed and sixteen wounded when separatists struck the bus with a  near a Ukrainian checkpoint.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (NP (NP (NNS Thousands)) (PP (IN of) (NP (NNPS Ukrainians))) (PP (IN in) (NP (NNP Kyiv)))) (VP (VBD took) (NP (NN part)) (PP (IN on) (NP (NNP Sunday))) (PP (IN in) (NP (NP (NNS marches)) (PP (IN in) (NP (NP (NN memory)) (PP (IN of) (NP (NP (VBN reported) (NNS victims)) (PP (IN of) (NP (NNS militants))))))))) (PP (IN in) (NP (NP (DT a) (NN tragedy)) (PP (IN on) (NP (NP (NNP January) (CD 13)) (PP (IN near) (PP (IN in) (NP (NNP Donetsk) (NNP Oblast))))))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150121" id="1870077" ><text>T
Democrat  was inaugurated yesterday as the 47th Governor of the U.S. commonwealth of Pennsylvania. He succeeds Republican Tom Corbett, whom he defeated in the election last November. The inauguration took place in front of the  in .</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (NP (NNP Democrat)) (VP (VBD was) (VP (VBN inaugurated) (NP (NN yesterday)) (PP (IN as) (NP (NP (DT the) (JJ 47th) (NN Governor)) (PP (IN of) (NP (NP (DT the) (NNP U.S.) (NN commonwealth)) (PP (IN of) (NP (NNP Pennsylvania))))))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150121" id="1871332" ><text>P
Three Baptist priests in Guinea were assaulted and held hostage yesterday by local villagers after being mistaken for campaigners promoting awareness about Ebola, the  has reported. They were visiting , a village in the sub-prefecture of , to spray insecticide for the treatment of wells and pit latrines. Locals reportedly thought they were bringing Ebola and attacked the priests. After the assault they were held hostage and had their vehicle set alight. ] / Dr. Frederick Murphy] Following the attack on the priests, town council workers were forced to evacuate as their building came under assault and was set fire to. A local report, not been independently verified, alleged a council worker was killed during the incident. Police intervened to arrest a number of the local villagers involved in the attacks but were met with hostility from those trying to stop the arrested being taken away.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (S (NP (NP (CD Three) (JJ Baptist) (NNS priests)) (PP (IN in) (NP (NNP Guinea)))) (VP (VBD were) (VP (VP (VBN assaulted)) (CC and) (VP (VBN held) (NP (NN hostage)) (NP (NN yesterday)) (PP (IN by) (NP (JJ local) (NNS villagers))) (PP (IN after) (S (VP (VBG being) (VP (VBN mistaken) (PP (IN for) (S (NP (NNS campaigners)) (VP (VBG promoting) (NP (NP (NN awareness)) (PP (IN about) (NP (NNP Ebola))))))))))))))) (, ,) (NP (DT the)) (VP (VBZ has) (VP (VBN reported))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150124" id="1876406" ><text>U
Representatives of the United Nations Security Council's (UNSC) fifteen member states flew to Haiti yesterday. The nation is moving to hold new elections with President Michel Martelly presently ruling by decree. ]] Martelly swore in a new Provisional Electoral Council (CEP) of nine members yesterday. It is Martelly's fifth CEP in four years. Last month a presidential commission recommended the prior CEP's resignation as part of a package of measures to move the country towards new elections. The commission was Martelly's response to widespread anti-regime protests that started in October. The sometimes-violent protests were triggered by failure to hold elections, some due since 2011.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (NP (NP (NNS Representatives)) (PP (IN of) (NP (NP (NP (DT the) (NNP United) (NNP Nations) (NNP Security) (NNP Council) (POS 's)) (PRN (-LRB- -LRB-) (NNP UNSC) (-RRB- -RRB-))) (CD fifteen) (NN member) (NNS states)))) (VP (VBD flew) (PP (TO to) (NP (NNP Haiti))) (NP (NN yesterday))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150127" id="1882772" ><text>G
Greek singer  died on Sunday in Athens.  The 68-year-old Roussos, born in Egypt, died in a private hospital. No official cause of death has been announced but the hospital said he had been there for some time. Roussos reached international fame in the 1960s and 70s. His hits included , Quand je t'aime, and Goodbye.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (NP (JJ Greek) (NN singer)) (VP (VBD died) (PP (IN on) (NP (NP (NNP Sunday)) (PP (IN in) (NP (NNP Athens)))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150130" id="1890866" ><text>S
Astronomers reported on Tuesday in The Astrophysical Journal they have found an ancient solar system with several Earth-like .  They said the system dates roughly to the formation of the  galaxy. They found the planets orbiting around , about 117  from . Researchers investigated Kepler-444 with NASA's Kepler telescope using a method called .</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (NP (NP (NP (NP (NNS Astronomers)) (VP (VBD reported) (PP (IN on) (NP (NNP Tuesday))) (PP (IN in) (NP (DT The) (JJ Astrophysical) (NNP Journal))))) (SBAR (S (NP (PRP they)) (VP (VBP have) (VP (VBN found) (NP (DT an) (JJ ancient) (JJ solar) (NN system)) (PP (IN with) (NP (ADJP (JJ several) (JJ Earth-like))))))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150131" id="1893549" ><text>C
]] Conductor Israel Yinon died yesterday after collapsing during a performance in Switzerland. The Israeli conductor was directing an orchestra in the city of  when he suddenly collapsed and fell head first off of the platform. No official cause of death has been announced. He was 59 years old.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (NP (-RRB- -RSB-) (-RRB- -RSB-) (NNP Conductor) (NNP Israel) (NNP Yinon)) (VP (VBD died) (NP (NN yesterday)) (PP (IN after) (S (VP (VBG collapsing) (PP (IN during) (NP (NP (DT a) (NN performance)) (PP (IN in) (NP (NNP Switzerland))))))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150131" id="1894746" ><text>G
An explosion on Thursday morning destroyed a state maternity hospital in Mexico City, Mexico. A nurse and two babies are dead.  Initially reports placed the fatalities at seven. Local officials including Mexico City Health Secretary Armando Ahued and Mayor Miguel Angel Mancera have since revised the figure downwards. Over 70 people including 20 infants are wounded. Around 100 people were in the building at the time.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (NP (NP (DT An) (NN explosion)) (PP (IN on) (NP (NNP Thursday) (NN morning)))) (VP (VBD destroyed) (NP (NP (DT a) (NN state) (NN maternity) (NN hospital)) (PP (IN in) (NP (NP (NNP Mexico) (NNP City)) (, ,) (NP (NNP Mexico)))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150131" id="1894879" ><text>R
A  was found dead in the Philippines on Wednesday.  There have been only fifteen confirmed sightings in the nation and around 60 worldwide.  ]] The fifteen-foot male was found after reportedly becoming entangled with a fishing net near the Barangay Marigondon neighborhood of ,  province. Its body was encased with ice pending a necropsy. The cause of death was not immediately clear.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (NP (DT A)) (VP (VBD was) (VP (VBN found) (S (ADJP (JJ dead))) (PP (IN in) (NP (DT the) (NNPS Philippines))) (PP (IN on) (NP (NNP Wednesday))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150131" id="1895169" ><text>S
South African Justice Minister  yesterday announced he is granting parole to , an -era assassin who has spent twenty years in prison.  After South Africa's first democratic elections in 1994 de Kock was arrested and subsequently detailed his actions to the nation's  (TRC). As head of a  'counter-insurgency' unit de Kock took responsibility for murdering and torturing dissidents opposed to white-only rule. His methods included bombings, shootings, and stabbings and he operated internationally and at home. His revelations earned him the nickname "Prime Evil".</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (NP (JJ South) (JJ African) (NNP Justice) (NNP Minister)) (NP (NN yesterday)) (VP (VBD announced) (SBAR (S (NP (PRP he)) (VP (VBZ is) (VP (VBG granting) (NP (NN parole)) (S (VP (TO to) (, ,) (NP (NP (DT an) (: -) (NN era) (NN assassin)) (SBAR (WHNP (WP who)) (S (VP (VBZ has) (VP (VBN spent) (NP (CD twenty) (NNS years)) (PP (IN in) (NP (NN prison))))))))))))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150201" id="1895857" ><text>F
]] A fire Friday night and Saturday morning caused major damage to the  in Moscow, Russia. It is among the nation's largest academic libraries.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (NP (-RRB- -RSB-) (-RRB- -RSB-) (NP (NP (DT A) (NN fire) (NNP Friday) (NN night)) (CC and) (NP (NNP Saturday) (NN morning)))) (VP (VBD caused) (NP (NP (JJ major) (NN damage)) (PP (TO to) (NP (DT the) (PP (IN in) (NP (NP (NNP Moscow)) (, ,) (NP (NNP Russia)))))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150201" id="1897929" ><text>R
, the President who oversaw German reunification in 1990, was announced to have died yesterday. He was 94.  von Weizs√§cker served as a Nazi soldier during World War II, earning promotions and an . He would later describe Germany's defeat as a liberation and encouraged his countrymen to acknowledge their collective past, including the . Following a business and law career he turned to politics. He joined the  and served as mayor of  before his 1984 election as President.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (, ,) (NP (NP (DT the) (NNP President)) (SBAR (WHNP (WP who)) (S (VP (VBP oversaw) (NP (JJ German) (NN reunification)) (PP (IN in) (NP (CD 1990))))))) (, ,) (VP (VBD was) (VP (VBN announced) (S (VP (TO to) (VP (VB have) (VP (VBN died) (NP (NN yesterday)))))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150203" id="1902570" ><text>C
Connecticut murder convict Robert Courchesne, who had a death sentence overturned by the , collapsed in prison yesterday. He died in hospital an hour later. ]] Courchesne, now 57, stabbed heavily pregnant Demetris Rodgers to death in 1998. In 2004 he was convicted of her murder and that of her unborn baby, delivered minutes after the murder by . Baby Antonia Rodgers spent over a month on life support before death was confirmed. Using legislation that provided the death penalty to multiple murderers the court sentenced Courchesne to death.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (NP (NNP Connecticut) (NN murder)) (VP (VP (VB convict) (NP (NP (NNP Robert) (NNP Courchesne)) (, ,) (SBAR (WHNP (WP who)) (S (VP (VBD had) (NP (NP (DT a) (NN death) (NN sentence)) (VP (VBN overturned) (PP (IN by) (NP (DT the)))))))) (, ,))) (VP (VBD collapsed) (PP (IN in) (NP (NN prison))) (NP (NN yesterday)))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150206" id="1908838" ><text>S
A Scottish university is investigating after several dozen members of its football club reportedly used  as part of costuming for a social event yesterday. Representatives from the , located in central Scotland, has said it has "zero-tolerance" for racism and is "disappointed that the actions of a few are tarnishing the [university's] reputation".</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (NP (DT A) (JJ Scottish) (NN university)) (VP (VBZ is) (VP (VBG investigating) (SBAR (IN after) (S (NP (JJ several) (NN dozen) (NNS members)) (IN of) (NP (PRP$ its) (NN football) (NN club)) (ADVP (RB reportedly)) (VP (VBN used) (PP (IN as) (NP (NP (NN part)) (PP (IN of) (NP (NN costuming))))) (PP (IN for) (NP (DT a) (JJ social) (NN event))) (NP (NN yesterday))))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150207" id="1909652" ><text>M
England's  yesterday appealed to the public for information to track down a man who stole a woman's purse after she was fatally injured by a lorry.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (NP (NP (NNP England) (POS 's)) (NN yesterday)) (VP (VBD appealed) (PP (TO to) (NP (DT the) (NN public))) (SBAR (IN for) (S (NP (NN information)) (VP (TO to) (VP (VB track) (PRT (RP down)) (NP (NP (DT a) (NN man)) (SBAR (WHNP (WP who)) (S (VP (VBD stole) (NP (NP (DT a) (NN woman) (POS 's)) (NN purse)) (SBAR (IN after) (S (NP (PRP she)) (VP (VBD was) (ADVP (RB fatally)) (VP (VBN injured) (PP (IN by) (NP (DT a) (NN lorry)))))))))))))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150207" id="1910371" ><text>C
Police detained a nine-year-old after a blaze started in a wholesale market in , , southern China on Thursday afternoon. Seventeen died. ]] According to police the child was playing with matches in a warehouse on the top-floor of the four-storey Yiwu Commodity Mall. Soon the entire floor was engulfed, leading to an eighteen-hour  mission involving 270 firefighters with 45 vehicles. Nine market managers have also been detained.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (NP (NNP Police)) (VP (VBD detained) (NP (DT a) (JJ nine-year-old)) (SBAR (IN after) (S (NP (DT a) (NN blaze)) (VP (VBD started) (PP (IN in) (NP (NP (DT a) (JJ wholesale) (NN market)) (PP (IN in) (NP (, ,) (, ,) (JJ southern) (NNP China))))) (PP (IN on) (NP (NNP Thursday) (NN afternoon))))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150207" id="1910958" ><text>T
]] The death toll from Wednesday's plane crash in , Taiwan reached 40 today with the recovery of five more bodies.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (NP (NP (-RRB- -RSB-) (-RRB- -RSB-) (DT The) (NN death) (NN toll)) (PP (IN from) (NP (NP (NNP Wednesday) (POS 's)) (NN plane) (NN crash))) (S (IN in) (, ,) (NP (NNP Taiwan)) (VP (VBD reached) (NP (CD 40)) (NP (NN today)) (PP (IN with) (NP (NP (DT the) (NN recovery)) (PP (IN of) (NP (CD five) (JJR more) (NNS bodies))))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150208" id="1912885" ><text>C
Niki Quasney, who together with wife Amy Sandler became the first married gay couple in Indiana, died of cancer on Thursday. She was 38. The death was announced today by the law firm that assisted her.  Indiana, US had only recognised their marriage last year after a  judge granted their emergency request. They wed in 2013 in Massachusetts, two years after an Illinois civil union.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (NP (NP (NP (NNP Niki) (NNP Quasney)) (, ,) (SBAR (WHNP (WP who)) (S (VP (ADVP (RB together)) (PP (IN with) (NP (NN wife) (NNP Amy) (NNP Sandler))) (VBD became) (NP (NP (DT the) (JJ first) (JJ married) (JJ gay) (NN couple)) (PP (IN in) (NP (NNP Indiana)))) (, ,) (VP (VBD died) (PP (IN of) (NP (NN cancer))) (PP (IN on) (NP (NNP Thursday)))))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150208" id="1912987" ><text>D
Divers yesterday recovered three bodies from December's air disaster in the Java Sea. Added to four retrieved on Friday, they bring the total to 100. An additional 62 victims remain to be recovered. ]] There were no survivors when Indonesia AirAsia Flight 8501 crashed on December 28. The six-year-old  was 40 minutes from Juanda International Airport with 155 passengers and seven crew, bound for Singapore's Changi International Airport. Most were Indonesians, with three South Koreans, one Malaysian, one Brit and one French person on board.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (NP (NNS Divers)) (NP (NN yesterday)) (VP (VBD recovered) (NP (CD three) (NNS bodies)) (PP (IN from) (NP (NP (NP (NNP December) (POS 's)) (NN air) (NN disaster)) (PP (IN in) (NP (DT the) (NNP Java) (NNP Sea)))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150210" id="1915694" ><text>F
Four people have died and at least four more have been seriously injured after a  hit multiple vehicles and two pedestrians in  in  England. The incident occurred at around 1600  yesterday when the truck rolled down a hill on Lansdown Lane in the city's  district in what witness accounts given to police suggest was an accident avoidance attempt.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (S (NP (CD Four) (NNS people)) (VP (VBP have) (VP (VP (VBN died)) (CC and) (NP (QP (IN at) (JJS least) (CD four)) (JJR more))))) (VBP have) (S (VP (VBN been) (VP (ADVP (RB seriously)) (VBN injured) (PP (IN after) (NP (NP (DT a) (NN hit) (JJ multiple) (NNS vehicles)) (CC and) (NP (NP (CD two) (NNS pedestrians)) (PP (IN in) (PP (IN in) (NP (NNP England)))))))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150211" id="1919766" ><text>T
Two men were shot during a robbery at a car stereo and alarm business in the city of Houston, Texas yesterday evening, according to police. One of the men, Abdullah Shakur, 65, later died at a local hospital.  The other man, Samer Salam, 32, was reportedly in critical condition late Tuesday evening.  ]] Police said three robbers carried out the attack, each wearing masks,  Reportedly, the store employees resisted. No suspects had been named as of 1:30pm local time Wednesday.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (FRAG (S (NP (CD Two) (NNS men)) (VP (VBD were) (VP (VBN shot) (PP (IN during) (NP (DT a) (NN robbery))) (PP (IN at) (NP (NP (DT a) (NN car) (NN stereo)) (CC and) (NP (NN alarm) (NN business)))) (PP (IN in) (NP (NP (DT the) (NN city)) (PP (IN of) (NP (NNP Houston)))))))) (, ,) (NP (NP (NNP Texas)) (NP (NN yesterday) (NN evening))) (, ,) (PP (VBG according) (PP (TO to) (NP (NNS police)))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150211" id="1920217" ><text>I
A military helicopter crashed in Jammu and Kashmir today. Two people, believed to be the pilots, are dead. ]] Both bodies are too burned for immediate identification. The  caught fire after going down in a forest in . The crash at around 7:43p.m.  was during night training over .  personnel reached the wreckage in the Laman/ forest at around 9:00p.m.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (NP (DT A) (JJ military) (NN helicopter)) (VP (VBD crashed) (PP (IN in) (NP (NP (NNP Jammu)) (CC and) (NP (NNP Kashmir)))) (NP (NN today))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150212" id="1922425" ><text>D
] advocate Santiago Canton] Yesterday's  discovery of a bound man, believed to be of Haitian ancestry, hanged from a tree in , Dominican Republic has drawn attention to anti-Hatian sentiments in the nation.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (NP (NP (-RRB- -RSB-) (NN advocate) (NNP Santiago) (NNP Canton)) (PP (-RRB- -RSB-) (NP (NP (NP (NN Yesterday) (POS 's)) (NN discovery)) (PP (IN of) (NP (NP (DT a) (VBN bound) (NN man)) (, ,) (VP (VBN believed) (S (VP (TO to) (VP (VB be) (PP (IN of) (NP (NP (JJ Haitian) (NN ancestry)) (, ,) (VP (VBN hanged) (PP (IN from) (NP (DT a) (NN tree))) (S (IN in) (, ,) (NP (NNP Dominican) (NNP Republic)) (VP (VBZ has) (VP (VBN drawn) (NP (NN attention)) (PP (TO to) (NP (NP (JJ anti-Hatian) (NNS sentiments)) (PP (IN in) (NP (DT the) (NN nation))))))))))))))))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150214" id="1925900" ><text>U
A  Utah study published on Tuesday in  suggests  may increase  rates. ]] The team analysed suicide records for over 1,500 people from , Utah from 2000 through 2010. Comparing to air pollution exposure in the three days prior to death the scientists noticed an increase of 20% for deaths amongst those exposed to high .</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (PRN (S (NP (NP (DT A) (NNP Utah) (NN study)) (VP (VBN published) (PP (IN on) (NP (NNP Tuesday))) (PP (IN in) (NP (VBZ suggests))))) (VP (MD may) (VP (VB increase) (NP (NNS rates)))) (. .) (-RRB- -RSB-)) (-RRB- -RSB-)))</parse><sentence date="20150215" id="1927456" ><text>P
]] Police in Denmark have shot dead a man they believe was responsible for two gun attacks that killed two people in  yesterday. Police had kept a property in the  district of the city under surveillance. When the man returned to the property, they confronted him and shot him in the ensuing fire fight.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (NP (NP (-RRB- -RSB-) (-RRB- -RSB-) (NNS Police)) (PP (IN in) (NP (NNP Denmark)))) (VP (VBP have) (VP (VBN shot) (PRT (RP dead)) (NP (NP (DT a) (NN man)) (SBAR (S (NP (PRP they)) (VP (VBP believe) (SBAR (S (VP (VBD was) (ADJP (JJ responsible) (PP (IN for) (NP (NP (CD two) (NN gun) (NNS attacks)) (SBAR (WHNP (WDT that)) (S (VP (VBD killed) (NP (CD two) (NNS people)) (PP (IN in) (NP (NN yesterday)))))))))))))))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150215" id="1927841" ><text>N
Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu has today called for European Jews to emigrate to Israel following the attack on a synagogue in  yesterday. The Israeli government is to discuss a plan to allocate 46 million (40 million) of funds to aid immigration by Jews in France, Belgium and Ukraine.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (NP (JJ Israeli) (NNP Prime) (NNP Minister) (NNP Benjamin) (NNP Netanyahu)) (VP (VBZ has) (NP (NN today)) (VP (VBN called) (SBAR (IN for) (S (NP (JJ European) (NNPS Jews)) (VP (TO to) (VP (VB emigrate) (PP (TO to) (NP (NNP Israel))) (PP (VBG following) (NP (NP (DT the) (NN attack)) (PP (IN on) (NP (NP (DT a) (NN synagogue)) (PP (IN in) (NP (NN yesterday))))))))))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150218" id="1930076" ><text>P
Pakistan released 173 inmates to Indian authorities at the Wagah border on Monday, out of which 172 were fishermen. The Pakistani Government ordered the fishermen released from two Karachi jails on Sunday. Alleged violation of the Arabian Sea maritime boundary of Karachi]] led the fishermen to imprisonment in the Malir and Landhi District Jail.  Earlier during the week Indian Prime Minister Narendra Modi provided his warm greeting to Pakistan Prime Minister Nawaz Sharif and leaders of other nations in the  who are taking part in the 2015 . The Indian fishermen reportedly had completed the terms of their imprisonment sentences last year; Pakistan's Foreign Ministry released a statement on Monday expressing hope for release of Pakistanis whose sentences in India are complete.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (NP (NNP Pakistan)) (VP (VBD released) (NP (CD 173) (NNS inmates)) (PP (TO to) (NP (JJ Indian) (NNS authorities))) (PP (IN at) (NP (DT the) (NNP Wagah) (NN border))) (PP (IN on) (NP (NNP Monday))) (, ,) (PP (IN out) (WHPP (IN of) (WHNP (WDT which) (CD 172) (VBD were) (NNS fishermen))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150216" id="1930287" ><text>W
]] , highly regarded Welsh historian, has died at the age of 76. Davies worked closely with the British Broadcasting Corporation (BBC) during his career, often as a commentator on . As well as his work as a broadcaster he was also an author and a teacher at several universities across Wales.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (NP (-RRB- -RSB-) (-RRB- -RSB-) (, ,) (VP (ADVP (RB highly)) (VBN regarded) (NP (NNP Welsh) (NN historian))) (, ,)) (VP (VBZ has) (VP (VBN died) (PP (IN at) (NP (NP (DT the) (NN age)) (PP (IN of) (NP (CD 76))))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150221" id="1938726" ><text>H
, an executive producer on the comedy television series , has been found dead. The 30-year-old was found unresponsive at his home in Los Angeles by his assistant on Thursday. He was pronounced dead at the scene. Police have announced they are investigating the possibility of a drug overdose.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (, ,) (NP (NP (DT an) (NN executive) (NN producer)) (PP (IN on) (NP (DT the) (NN comedy) (NN television) (NN series)))) (, ,) (VP (VBZ has) (VP (VBN been) (VP (VBN found) (S (ADJP (JJ dead)))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150226" id="1953770" ><text>S
The US carrier Southwest Airlines, the world's largest low-cost carrier, announced grounding 128 planes on Tuesday because the planes had not be adequately inspected.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (NP (NP (DT The) (NNP US) (NN carrier) (NNP Southwest) (NNP Airlines)) (, ,) (NP (NP (DT the) (NN world) (POS 's)) (JJS largest) (JJ low-cost) (NN carrier)) (, ,)) (VP (VBD announced) (NP (NN grounding) (CD 128) (NNS planes)) (PP (IN on) (NP (NNP Tuesday))) (SBAR (IN because) (S (NP (DT the) (NNS planes)) (VP (VBD had) (RB not) (VP (VB be) (VP (ADVP (RB adequately)) (VBN inspected))))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150303" id="1964089" ><text>F
English footballer  has been arrested on suspicion of having sex with a girl under the age of 16. Johnson, who currently plays for  , was arrested yesterday morning at his home.  Police confirmed they had arrested a "27-year-old man [...] on suspicion of sexual activity with a girl under 16."</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (NP (NNP English) (NN footballer)) (VP (VBZ has) (VP (VBN been) (VP (VBN arrested) (PP (IN on) (NP (NP (NN suspicion)) (PP (IN of) (S (VP (VBG having) (NP (NN sex)) (PP (IN with) (NP (NP (DT a) (NN girl)) (PP (IN under) (NP (NP (DT the) (NN age)) (PP (IN of) (NP (CD 16))))))))))))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150304" id="1966857" ><text>B
, a central figure in an , Georgia public schools cheating scandal since 2009, died at the age of 68 on Monday. The cause of death was reported as , a disease she had been suffering from since 2004. At the time of her death Hall was still facing criminal charges relating to the cheating scandal.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (, ,) (NP (DT a) (JJ central) (NN figure)) (IN in) (DT an) (, ,) (NP (NP (NNP Georgia) (JJ public) (NNS schools)) (VP (VBG cheating) (NP (NN scandal)) (PP (IN since) (NP (CD 2009))))) (, ,) (VP (VBD died) (PP (IN at) (NP (NP (DT the) (NN age)) (PP (IN of) (NP (CD 68))))) (PP (IN on) (NP (NNP Monday)))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150304" id="1967652" ><text>E
Edward Snowden, a   (NSA) whistle-blower who has been in exile since 2013, would like to return to the United States providing he is guaranteed a "fair and impartial trial", said Anatoly Kucherena, his Russian lawyer, yesterday.  The  has promised Snowden he will not be  if he is convicted under the , however, Kucherena says, he has not been promised the fair trial he seeks. Kucherena also said the US Attorney General does not have legal power to enforce the promise of no execution. Reportedly, "fair", to Snowden's lawyers, requires he would not be tried under the Espionage Act. Snowden has been on the run since leaking classified information regarding the NSA's mass electronic surveillance of the US population to the mainstream media.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (SINV (S (NP (NP (NNP Edward) (NNP Snowden)) (, ,) (NP (NP (DT a) (PRN (-LRB- -LRB-) (NNP NSA) (-RRB- -RRB-)) (NN whistle-blower)) (SBAR (WHNP (WP who)) (S (VP (VBZ has) (VP (VBN been) (PP (IN in) (NP (NN exile))) (PP (IN since) (NP (CD 2013)))))))) (, ,)) (VP (MD would) (VP (VB like) (S (VP (TO to) (VP (VB return) (PP (TO to) (NP (DT the) (NNP United) (NNPS States))) (S (VP (VBG providing) (SBAR (S (NP (PRP he)) (VP (VBZ is) (VP (VBN guaranteed) (NP (DT a) (`` ``) (ADJP (JJ fair) (CC and) (JJ impartial)) (NN trial) ('' '')))))))))))))) (, ,) (VP (VBD said)) (NP (NP (NNP Anatoly) (NNP Kucherena)) (, ,) (NP (PRP$ his) (JJ Russian) (NN lawyer)) (, ,)) (NP (NN yesterday)) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150304" id="1968436" ><text>E
Billionaire Microsoft co-founder  yesterday announced his ocean exploration team has found a wreck thought to be the , one of the largest warships ever built. The Musashi was a Japanese battleship sunk by US forces during World War Two.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (NP (NP (NN Billionaire) (NNP Microsoft) (NN co-founder)) (SBAR (S (NP (NN yesterday)) (VP (VBD announced) (SBAR (S (NP (PRP$ his) (NN ocean) (NN exploration) (NN team)) (VP (VBZ has) (VP (VBN found) (SBAR (S (NP (DT a) (NN wreck)) (VP (VBD thought) (S (VP (TO to) (VP (VB be) (NP (DT the) (, ,) (NP (NP (CD one)) (PP (IN of) (NP (NP (DT the) (JJS largest) (NNS warships)) (VP (ADVP (RB ever)) (VBN built))))))))))))))))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150305" id="1968775" ><text>S
]"] Scottish footballer  died in an English hospital on Monday. He was 80.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (NP (-RRB- -RSB-) ('' '') (-RRB- -RSB-) (JJ Scottish) (NN footballer)) (VP (VBD died) (PP (IN in) (NP (DT an) (JJ English) (NN hospital))) (PP (IN on) (NP (NNP Monday)))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150304" id="1968946" ><text>A
The  yesterday ordered all judges to halt in issuing same-sex marriage licenses in the state. The ruling goes against an earlier order by the United States Supreme Court, allowing judges to issue same-sex couples a marriage license.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (NP (DT The) (NN yesterday)) (VP (VBD ordered) (S (NP (DT all) (NNS judges)) (VP (TO to) (VP (VB halt) (PP (IN in) (S (VP (VBG issuing) (NP (NP (JJ same-sex) (NN marriage) (NNS licenses)) (PP (IN in) (NP (DT the) (NN state))))))))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150305" id="1969228" ><text>S
"] , the former  of Ukraine has been arrested in Spain on charges of fraud and embezzlement. Kolobov was wanted, along with former President Viktor Yanukovych, accused of fraud which cost Ukraine billions of dollars in assets. The Spanish civil guard arrested him on Wednesday, at a flat in , in the .</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S ('' '') (-RRB- -RSB-) (, ,) (NP (NP (DT the) (JJ former)) (PP (IN of) (NP (NNP Ukraine)))) (VP (VBZ has) (VP (VBN been) (VP (VBN arrested) (PP (IN in) (NP (NNP Spain))) (PP (IN on) (NP (NP (NNS charges)) (PP (IN of) (NP (NN fraud) (CC and) (NN embezzlement)))))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150308" id="1974065" ><text>D
]] A Delta Air Lines passenger jet skidded off the runway at New York City's LaGuardia Airport in snowy weather on Thursday, causing a shutdown of the airport, according to officials.  The jetliner was carrying 127 passengers and five crew.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (-RRB- -RSB-) (-RRB- -RSB-) (NP (DT A) (NNP Delta) (NNP Air) (NNPS Lines) (NN passenger) (NN jet)) (VP (VBD skidded) (PRT (RP off)) (NP (NP (DT the) (NN runway)) (PP (IN at) (NP (NP (NNP New) (NNP York) (NNP City) (POS 's)) (NNP LaGuardia) (NNP Airport))) (PP (IN in) (NP (NP (JJ snowy) (NN weather)) (PP (IN on) (NP (NNP Thursday)))))) (, ,) (S (VP (VBG causing) (NP (NP (DT a) (NN shutdown)) (PP (IN of) (NP (DT the) (NN airport)))))) (, ,) (PP (VBG according) (PP (TO to) (NP (NNS officials))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150309" id="1978009" ><text>F
Five people, including two Europeans, have been killed by gunmen during an attack on a bar in , the capital city of Mali, early on Sunday morning. At least nine others were injured during the attack in which the assailants used machine guns and grenades.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (NP (NP (CD Five) (NNS people)) (, ,) (PP (VBG including) (NP (CD two) (NNPS Europeans))) (, ,)) (VP (VBP have) (VP (VBN been) (VP (VBN killed) (PP (IN by) (NP (NNS gunmen))) (PP (IN during) (NP (NP (DT an) (NN attack)) (PP (IN on) (NP (NP (DT a) (NN bar)) (PP (IN in) (NP (, ,) (NP (NP (DT the) (NN capital) (NN city)) (PP (IN of) (NP (NNP Mali))) (, ,) (ADVP (RB early) (PP (IN on) (NP (NNP Sunday) (NN morning)))))))))))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150309" id="1978129" ><text>N
Military forces from Chad and Niger yesterday engaged Boko Haram militants within the borders of Nigeria. This follows African Union endorsement on Friday of the creation of an 8,000-plus strong regional force to combat the threat posed by the militant group.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (NP (NP (JJ Military) (NNS forces)) (PP (IN from) (NP (NNP Chad) (CC and) (NNP Niger)))) (NP (NN yesterday)) (VP (VBD engaged) (NP (NNP Boko) (NNP Haram) (NNS militants)) (PP (IN within) (NP (NP (DT the) (NNS borders)) (PP (IN of) (NP (NNP Nigeria)))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150310" id="1980102" ><text>Z
, the current President of Zambia, is to undergo medical treatment aboard after collapsing while on stage in  on Sunday during a ceremony for International Women's Day. The Presidency announced yesterday that Lungu will have throat surgery abroad.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (, ,) (NP (NP (DT the) (JJ current) (NN President)) (PP (IN of) (NP (NNP Zambia)))) (, ,) (VP (VBZ is) (S (VP (TO to) (VP (VB undergo) (NP (JJ medical) (NN treatment)) (PP (IN aboard) (PP (IN after) (S (VP (VBG collapsing) (SBAR (IN while) (S (PP (IN on) (NP (NP (NN stage)) (PP (IN in) (PP (IN on) (NP (NNP Sunday)))))))) (PP (IN during) (NP (NP (DT a) (NN ceremony)) (PP (IN for) (NP (NP (NNP International) (NNP Women) (POS 's)) (NN Day))))))))))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150310" id="1980223" ><text>S
died, at the age of 59, on Sunday of  cancer, a disease he was diagnosed with in 2012. One of the co-creators of the television series , Simon helped create the hugely successful series in 1989 alongside  and . He left the show in 1993 after roles as writer and character developer among others.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (VP (VBD died) (, ,) (PP (IN at) (NP (NP (DT the) (NN age)) (PP (IN of) (NP (CD 59))))) (, ,) (S (PP (IN on) (NP (NP (NNP Sunday)) (PP (IN of) (NP (NN cancer))))) (, ,) (NP (DT a) (NN disease)) (NP (PRP he)) (VP (VBD was) (VP (VBN diagnosed) (PP (IN with)) (PP (IN in) (NP (CD 2012))))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150312" id="1982440" ><text>U
The Associated Press (AP) reported on Tuesday the U.S.  is conducting drone exercises over Washington, D.C. to defend against  being flown over the area.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (NP (NP (DT The) (NNP Associated) (NNP Press)) (PRN (-LRB- -LRB-) (NP (NNP AP)) (-RRB- -RRB-))) (VP (VP (VBN reported) (PP (IN on) (NP (NNP Tuesday)))) (SBAR (S (NP (DT the) (NNP U.S.)) (VP (VBZ is) (VP (VBG conducting) (NP (NN drone) (NNS exercises)) (PP (IN over) (NP (NP (NNP Washington)) (, ,) (NP (NNP D.C.)))) (S (VP (TO to) (VP (VB defend) (PP (IN against) (S (VP (VBG being) (VP (VBN flown) (PP (IN over) (NP (DT the) (NN area))))))))))))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150312" id="1982805" ><text>T
Three French sport stars are among the dead following a  on Monday in , Argentina. In total, ten people died after the crash, which involved two helicopters. The dead included passengers and both pilots in the mid-air collision. The victims were taking part in the French reality television show '' when the accident happened.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (NP (CD Three) (JJ French) (NN sport) (NNS stars)) (VP (VBP are) (PP (IN among) (NP (DT the) (JJ dead))) (PP (VBG following) (NP (DT a) (PP (IN on) (NP (NNP Monday))))) (VP (IN in) (, ,) (NP (NNP Argentina)))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150311" id="1983470" ><text>H
, Ireland's Health Minister, introduced emergency legislation in the lower house of the Irish parliament yesterday evening, to negate the legal loophole created by a decision from Dublin's Court of Appeal that morning. Various hard drugs - including , ecstasy, and magic mushrooms - were rendered legal, following the law governing their prohibition being found to be unconstitutional.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (, ,) (NP (NP (NNP Ireland) (POS 's)) (NNP Health) (NNP Minister)) (, ,) (VP (VBD introduced) (NP (NN emergency) (NN legislation)) (PP (IN in) (NP (NP (DT the) (JJR lower) (NN house)) (PP (IN of) (NP (DT the) (JJ Irish) (NN parliament))))) (NP (NN yesterday) (NN evening)) (, ,) (S (VP (TO to) (VP (VB negate) (NP (NP (DT the) (JJ legal) (NN loophole)) (VP (VBN created) (PP (IN by) (NP (NP (DT a) (NN decision)) (PP (IN from) (NP (NP (NP (NNP Dublin) (POS 's)) (NNP Court)) (PP (IN of) (NP (NNP Appeal))) (NP (WDT that) (NN morning)))))))))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150311" id="1983793" ><text>B
Jeremy Clarkson, one of the presenters on the BBC's motoring programme '' has been suspended by the corporation. Clarkson, responsible for several prior controversies, was suspended Tuesday, after allegedly 'punching' a producer last week. The next two episodes of 'Top Gear' have been pulled from broadcast, with a third - the season finale - also unlikely to be shown.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (NP (NP (NP (NNP Jeremy) (NNP Clarkson)) (, ,) (NP (NP (CD one)) (PP (IN of) (NP (DT the) (NNS presenters))) (SBAR (IN on) (S (NP (NP (DT the) (NNP BBC) (POS 's)) (NN motoring) (NN programme)) ('' '') (VP (VBZ has) (VP (VBN been) (VP (VBN suspended) (PP (IN by) (NP (DT the) (NN corporation)))))))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150313" id="1983903" ><text>S
On Wednesday, Vuyo Mvoko, a television journalist, was mugged moments before he was due to start a live broadcast in Johannesburg, South Africa. During the incident, two men approached Mvoko and demanded his mobile phone while he stood near the . When Mvoko refused to hand over the phone he was reportedly threatened with a gun. Video footage caught the mugging and has been publicly released.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (PP (IN On) (NP (NNP Wednesday))) (, ,) (NP (NP (NNP Vuyo) (NNP Mvoko)) (, ,) (NP (DT a) (NN television) (NN journalist)) (, ,)) (VP (VBD was) (VP (VBN mugged) (NP (NNS moments)) (SBAR (IN before) (S (NP (PRP he)) (VP (VBD was) (ADJP (JJ due) (S (VP (TO to) (VP (VB start) (NP (NP (DT a) (JJ live) (NN broadcast)) (PP (IN in) (NP (NNP Johannesburg))))))))))))) (, ,) (NP (NNP South) (NNP Africa)) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150314" id="1984595" ><text>I
has been sacked as manager of . His sacking, announced on Tuesday, has come after a 1-;4 defeat to . on March 7. He had managed Millwall since January 2014. Former player  has been placed in charge until season's end.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (VP (VBZ has) (VP (VBN been) (VP (VBN sacked) (PP (IN as) (NP (NP (NN manager)) (PP (IN of))))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150314" id="1987211" ><text>B
] British author , best known for the  series of , has died at the age of 66. Pratchett was diagnosed with a rare form of  in 2007, following his diagnosis he donated to Alzheimer's charities and became a public face of the disease</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (NP (NP (-RRB- -RSB-) (JJ British) (NN author)) (, ,) (ADJP (RB best) (VBN known) (PP (IN for) (NP (NP (DT the) (NN series)) (PP (IN of))))) (, ,)) (VP (VBZ has) (VP (VBN died) (PP (IN at) (NP (NP (DT the) (NN age)) (PP (IN of) (NP (CD 66))))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150314" id="1990932" ><text>C
J.C.X Simon, one of the convicted '', has died at the age of 69 in . His death came shortly before midnight on Thursday, with the cause remaining unknown. Simon was convicted alongside three others for the killing spree known as the 'Zebra Killings' in San Francisco in the 1970s.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (NP (NP (NNP J.C.X) (NNP Simon)) (, ,) (NP (NP (CD one)) (PP (IN of) (NP (DT the) (VBN convicted) ('' '')))) (, ,)) (VP (VBZ has) (VP (VBN died) (PP (IN at) (NP (NP (DT the) (NN age)) (PP (IN of) (NP (CD 69))))) (PP (IN in)))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150316" id="1993465" ><text>X
, a former Chinese general who was once the second in command within the , died yesterday, according to Chinese state news agency . Xu, 71, was due to be prosecuted over  charges. The cause of death was announced as  .</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (SINV (, ,) (NP (NP (DT a) (JJ former) (JJ Chinese) (NN general)) (SBAR (WHNP (WP who)) (S (VP (VBD was) (ADVP (RB once)) (NP (NP (DT the) (JJ second)) (PP (IN in) (NP (NN command))) (PP (IN within) (NP (DT the)))))))) (, ,) (VP (VBD died)) (NP (NN yesterday)) (, ,) (PP (VBG according) (PP (TO to) (NP (JJ Chinese) (NN state) (NN news) (NN agency)))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150316" id="1993819" ><text>5
A bus carrying 60 passengers to a religious event in the  state of Brazil plunged over a cliff on Saturday evening. The driver reportedly lost control whilst approaching a curve, leading the bus to fall 400 metres into a wooded area just ten kilometres away from , the final destination. Whilst the cause of the accident is not yet confirmed, police believe that the brakes on the vehicle may have failed.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (NP (NP (DT A) (NN bus)) (VP (VBG carrying) (NP (CD 60) (NNS passengers)) (PP (TO to) (NP (NP (DT a) (JJ religious) (NN event)) (PP (IN in) (NP (NP (DT the) (NN state)) (PP (IN of) (NP (NNP Brazil))))))))) (VP (VBD plunged) (PP (IN over) (NP (DT a) (NN cliff))) (PP (IN on) (NP (NNP Saturday) (NN evening)))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150322" id="2010199" ><text>L
The  cafe in Sydney, Australia reopened on Friday, after a siege at the cafe three months ago killed one of its employees, Tori Johnson, and a customer, Katrina Dawson.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (S (NP (NP (DT The) (NN cafe)) (PP (IN in) (NP (NP (NNP Sydney)) (, ,) (NP (NNP Australia))))) (VP (VBD reopened) (PP (IN on) (NP (NNP Friday))) (, ,) (SBAR (IN after) (S (NP (NP (DT a) (NN siege)) (PP (IN at) (NP (NP (DT the) (NN cafe)) (ADVP (NP (CD three) (NNS months)) (IN ago))))) (VP (VBD killed) (NP (NP (CD one)) (PP (IN of) (NP (NP (PRP$ its) (NNS employees)) (, ,) (NP (NNP Tori) (NNP Johnson)))))))))) (, ,) (CC and) (NP (NP (DT a) (NN customer)) (, ,) (NP (NNP Katrina) (NNP Dawson))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150324" id="2018130" ><text>S
Lee Kuan Yew, the first  of Singapore, has died at the age of 91. Considered the "founding father" of Singapore, Lee led Singapore through the aftermath of independence to become one of the world's richest nations. He died yesterday under treatment for  at the .</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (NP (NP (NNP Lee) (NNP Kuan) (NNP Yew)) (, ,) (NP (NP (DT the) (JJ first)) (PP (IN of) (NP (NNP Singapore)))) (, ,)) (VP (VBZ has) (VP (VBN died) (PP (IN at) (NP (NP (DT the) (NN age)) (PP (IN of) (NP (CD 91))))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150325" id="2020214" ><text>G
, an Airbus  carrying 150 passengers and crew, crashed into the  yesterday between  and . Officials said there were no survivors. The plane was flying to , Germany from , Spain. An emergency recovery team made its way to the crash site and reportedly recovered one of the plane's .</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (SBAR (, ,) (S (NP (NP (DT an) (NNP Airbus)) (VP (VBG carrying) (NP (CD 150) (NNS passengers) (CC and) (NN crew))) (, ,)) (VP (VBD crashed) (PP (IN into) (NP (DT the) (NN yesterday))) (ADVP (IN between) (CC and)))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150325" id="2020487" ><text>B
, an English singer and television personality, died on Monday, police reported that day. The 24-year-old Chris Hardman was found dead at an address in , .  said they were not treating it as a suspicious death. Hardman came to fame as Lil' Chris after appearing on the Channel 4 reality television show .</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (FRAG (, ,) (NP (NP (DT an) (NX (NX (JJ English) (NN singer)) (CC and) (NX (NN television) (NN personality)))) (, ,) (VP (VBD died) (PP (IN on) (NP (NNP Monday)))) (, ,) (NP (NP (NN police)) (VP (VBD reported) (NP (DT that) (NN day))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150327" id="2021162" ><text>U
The US state of Utah has reinstated the use of the  as the method of execution for prisoners on , eleven years after it was abolished. On Monday , the state's governor, signed into law legislation approving the firing squad as an alternative means of capital punishment if lethal injections are unavailable.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (FRAG (S (NP (NP (DT The) (NNP US) (NN state)) (PP (IN of) (NP (NNP Utah)))) (VP (VBZ has) (VP (VBN reinstated) (NP (NP (DT the) (NN use)) (PP (IN of) (NP (DT the))) (PP (IN as) (NP (NP (DT the) (NN method)) (PP (IN of) (NP (NP (NN execution)) (PP (IN for) (NP (NP (NNS prisoners)) (PP (IN on)))))))))))) (, ,) (SBAR (NP (NNS eleven) (NNS years)) (IN after) (S (NP (PRP it)) (VP (VBD was) (VP (VBN abolished))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150326" id="2024286" ><text>Z
, one of the members of British pop boy-band , has left the group after five years. The band confirmed yesterday that Malik has left the group with a statement on Facebook. They also announced they would continue with the remaining four members and their fifth album would be recorded later this year.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (, ,) (NP (NP (CD one)) (PP (IN of) (NP (NP (DT the) (NNS members)) (PP (IN of) (NP (JJ British) (NN pop) (NN boy-band)))))) (, ,) (VP (VBZ has) (VP (VBN left) (NP (DT the) (NN group)) (PP (IN after) (NP (CD five) (NNS years))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150329" id="2025426" ><text>O
Officials said on Thursday, after analyzing data from the Germanwings  , that the airbus crashed into the French  because its co-pilot deliberately crashed it.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (NP (NNS Officials)) (VP (VBD said) (PP (IN on) (NP (NNP Thursday))) (, ,) (PP (IN after) (S (VP (VBG analyzing) (NP (NNS data)) (PP (IN from) (NP (DT the) (NNP Germanwings)))))) (, ,) (SBAR (IN that) (S (NP (DT the) (NN airbus)) (VP (VBD crashed) (PP (IN into) (NP (DT the) (JJ French))) (SBAR (IN because) (S (NP (PRP$ its) (NNS co-pilot)) (ADVP (RB deliberately)) (VP (VBD crashed) (NP (PRP it))))))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150327" id="2025951" ><text>U
] The  of the  have concluded yesterday that the government must release a series of 27 letters sent by  to government ministers and that attempts to prevent their publication under the  have been unlawful.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (-RRB- -RSB-) (NP (DT The) (S (IN of) (DT the) (VP (VBP have) (VP (VBN concluded) (NP (NN yesterday)) (SBAR (SBAR (IN that) (S (NP (DT the) (NN government)) (VP (MD must) (VP (VB release) (NP (NP (NP (DT a) (NN series)) (PP (IN of) (NP (CD 27) (NNS letters)))) (VP (VBN sent) (PP (IN by)) (PP (TO to) (NP (NN government) (NNS ministers))))))))) (CC and) (SBAR (IN that) (NP (NNS attempts) (S (VP (TO to) (VP (VB prevent) (NP (PRP$ their) (NN publication)) (SBAR (IN under) (S (DT the) (VP (VBP have) (VP (VBN been) (ADJP (JJ unlawful)))))))))))))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150330" id="2029217" ><text>U
The  qualification match between Montenegro and Russia on Friday was abandoned after players and coaching staff got involved in a brawl. The match, at Montenegrin capital 's , was suspended within the first minute after the Russian goalkeeper was hit with a . The match re-started after a delay but was called off around the 66th minute when a brawl started.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (NP (NP (DT The) (NN qualification) (NN match)) (PP (IN between) (NP (NP (NNP Montenegro)) (CC and) (NP (NNP Russia)))) (PP (IN on) (NP (NNP Friday)))) (VP (VBD was) (VP (VBN abandoned) (SBAR (IN after) (S (NP (NP (NNS players)) (CC and) (NP (NN coaching) (NN staff))) (VP (VBD got) (VP (VBN involved) (PP (IN in) (NP (DT a) (NN brawl))))))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150401" id="2033650" ><text>S
A small plane, piloted by sixteen-year-old Ryan McCall, crashed near  in Virginia, at about 9:45 a.m.  Sunday morning, police said. He was killed in the accident.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (S (NP (NP (DT A) (JJ small) (NN plane)) (, ,) (VP (VBN piloted) (PP (IN by) (NP (JJ sixteen-year-old) (NNP Ryan) (NNP McCall)))) (, ,)) (VP (VBD crashed) (PP (IN near) (PP (IN in) (NP (NNP Virginia)))) (, ,) (PP (IN at) (NP (IN about) (CD 9:45) (RB a.m.) (NNP Sunday) (NN morning))))) (, ,) (NP (NN police)) (VP (VBD said)) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150331" id="2033651" ><text>F
The bodies of two adults and two children were found yesterday at a flat in Gibraltar in a possible murder-suicide. Two young girls, one aged four and the other only six weeks, were found stabbed alongside a British 31-year-old male and a Spanish 37-year-old female.  said despite opening up a crime investigation on the deaths they do not currently believe anyone else was involved.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (NP (NP (DT The) (NNS bodies)) (PP (IN of) (NP (NP (CD two) (NNS adults)) (CC and) (NP (CD two) (NNS children))))) (VP (VBD were) (VP (VBN found) (NP (NN yesterday)) (PP (IN at) (NP (NP (DT a) (JJ flat)) (PP (IN in) (NP (NNP Gibraltar))))) (PP (IN in) (NP (DT a) (JJ possible) (NN murder-suicide))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150404" id="2036735" ><text>M
Well-known  singer-songwriter  was found unconscious on Tuesday at her Los Angeles home, and immediately taken to hospital, according to reports. An update on her condition appeared yesterday on her website.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (S (NP (JJ Well-known) (NN singer-songwriter)) (VP (VBD was) (VP (VBN found) (S (ADJP (JJ unconscious))) (PP (IN on) (NP (NNP Tuesday))) (PP (IN at) (NP (PRP$ her) (NNP Los) (NNP Angeles) (NN home)))))) (, ,) (CC and) (VP (ADVP (RB immediately)) (VBN taken) (PP (TO to) (NP (NN hospital)))) (, ,) (PP (VBG according) (PP (TO to) (NP (NNS reports)))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150405" id="2043604" ><text>G
, gun control campaigner and widow of former US   , has died at the age of 73. Her death was announced by the . Brady died on Friday after a battle with  according to e-mails sent by her family.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (NP (NP (, ,) (NN gun) (NN control) (NN campaigner)) (CC and) (NP (NP (NN widow)) (PP (IN of) (NP (JJ former) (NNP US)))) (, ,)) (VP (VBZ has) (VP (VBN died) (PP (IN at) (NP (NP (DT the) (NN age)) (PP (IN of) (NP (CD 73))))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150409" id="2050520" ><text>P
A  twin engine aircraft crashed in an Illinois field on Tuesday while returning from an  NCAA basketball tournament.  All seven people on the plane were killed.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (NP (DT A) (JJ twin) (NN engine) (NN aircraft)) (VP (VBD crashed) (PP (IN in) (NP (DT an) (NNP Illinois) (NN field))) (PP (IN on) (NP (NNP Tuesday))) (SBAR (IN while) (S (VP (VBG returning) (PP (IN from) (NP (DT an) (NNP NCAA) (NN basketball) (NN tournament))))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150409" id="2055057" ><text>D
Jurors in the US federal criminal trial of  found him guilty yesterday of all 30 charges for the bombing of the Boston Marathon which occurred on April 15, 2013. The bombings killed three people and injured a further 264 people. Tsarnaev was also found guilty of shooting dead Sean Collier, an MIT police officer. The jury took eleven hours across two days to find Tsarnaev guilty.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (FRAG (NP (NP (NNP Jurors)) (PP (IN in) (NP (NP (DT the) (NNP US) (JJ federal) (JJ criminal) (NN trial)) (PP (IN of) (S (VP (VBN found) (S (NP (PRP him)) (VP (JJ guilty) (NP (NN yesterday)) (PP (IN of) (NP (NP (QP (DT all) (CD 30)) (NNS charges)) (PP (IN for) (NP (NP (DT the) (NN bombing)) (PP (IN of) (NP (NP (DT the) (NNP Boston) (NNP Marathon)) (SBAR (WHNP (WDT which)) (S (VP (VBD occurred) (PP (IN on) (NP (NP (NNP April) (CD 15)) (, ,) (NP (CD 2013))))))))))))))))))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150411" id="2056981" ><text>F
India's Ministry of External affairs yesterday announced the end of an evacuation effort which has rescued about 5,600 people from more than 40 countries from the conflict in Yemen.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (NP (NP (NP (NNP India) (POS 's)) (NNP Ministry)) (PP (IN of) (NP (JJ External) (NNS affairs))) (NP (NN yesterday))) (VP (VBD announced) (NP (NP (DT the) (NN end)) (PP (IN of) (NP (NP (DT an) (NN evacuation) (NN effort)) (SBAR (WHNP (WDT which)) (S (VP (VBZ has) (VP (VBN rescued) (NP (QP (IN about) (CD 5,600)) (NNS people)) (PP (IN from) (NP (QP (JJR more) (IN than) (CD 40)) (NNS countries))) (PP (IN from) (NP (NP (DT the) (NN conflict)) (PP (IN in) (NP (NNP Yemen))))))))))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150412" id="2058800" ><text>U
In Washington D.C., the U.S. Capitol building has reopened after shots were fired in front of it. For safety, no entry or exit was permitted from the building after a man committed suicide just before 2pm  yesterday. The lockdown lasted until around 3:50pm while members of the bomb squad investigated the man's backpack, suitcase, and the surrounding area.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (PP (IN In) (NP (NNP Washington) (NNP D.C.))) (, ,) (NP (DT the) (NNP U.S.) (NNP Capitol) (NN building)) (VP (VBZ has) (VP (VBN reopened) (SBAR (IN after) (S (NP (NNS shots)) (VP (VBD were) (VP (VBN fired) (PP (IN in) (NP (NP (NN front)) (PP (IN of) (NP (PRP it))))))))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150412" id="2059950" ><text>U
(S2) association football club have maintained a streak with their third home win at  in , Washington last night, this time against  (T2).</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (NP (PRN (-LRB- -LRB-) (NP (NN S2)) (-RRB- -RRB-)) (NN association) (NN football) (NN club)) (VP (VBP have) (VP (VBN maintained) (NP (DT a) (NN streak)) (S (PP (IN with) (NP (PRP$ their) (JJ third) (NN home))) (VP (VB win) (PP (IN at) (PP (IN in) (PRN (, ,) (NP (NP (NNP Washington)) (NP (JJ last) (NN night))) (, ,) (NP (NP (DT this) (NN time)) (PP (IN against) (PRN (-LRB- -LRB-) (NP (NN T2)) (-RRB- -RRB-))))))))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150414" id="2064031" ><text>A
Robert Penny, 83, yesterday was charged with the murder of his wife Margaret Penny and hairdresser Claire Acocks, twenty four years after their deaths at the Old London Coiffure hair salon in , Victoria in Australia.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (NP (NP (NNP Robert) (NNP Penny)) (, ,) (NP (CD 83)) (, ,)) (NP (NN yesterday)) (VP (VBD was) (VP (VP (VBN charged) (PP (IN with) (NP (NP (DT the) (NN murder)) (PP (IN of) (NP (NP (PRP$ his) (NN wife)) (NP (NNP Margaret) (NNP Penny)) (CC and) (NP (NN hairdresser) (NNP Claire) (NNP Acocks))))))) (, ,) (FRAG (NP (QP (CD twenty) (CD four)) (NNS years)) (IN after) (NP (PRP$ their) (NNS deaths)) (IN at) (NP (DT the) (NNP Old) (NNP London) (NNP Coiffure) (NN hair) (NN salon)) (IN in) (, ,) (NP (NP (NNP Victoria)) (PP (IN in) (NP (NNP Australia))))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150417" id="2067610" ><text>M
]] On Wednesday, the Mississippi State Board of Medical Licensure chose to let Doctor Carroll Frazier Landrum keep his physician's license, following an investigation sparked by an anonymous complaint. Media reported the Mississippi doctor has been working out of his Toyota  for about two years, making house calls to see patients.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (-RRB- -RSB-) (-RRB- -RSB-) (PP (IN On) (NP (NNP Wednesday))) (, ,) (NP (NP (DT the) (NNP Mississippi) (NNP State) (NNP Board)) (PP (IN of) (NP (NNP Medical) (NNP Licensure)))) (VP (VBD chose) (S (VP (TO to) (VP (VB let) (S (NP (NNP Doctor) (NNP Carroll) (NNP Frazier) (NNP Landrum)) (VP (VB keep) (NP (NP (PRP$ his) (NN physician) (POS 's)) (NN license)) (, ,) (PP (VBG following) (NP (NP (DT an) (NN investigation)) (VP (VBN sparked) (PP (IN by) (NP (DT an) (JJ anonymous) (NN complaint)))))))))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150418" id="2070183" ><text>G
Douglas Mark Hughes, a mailman for the United States , landed his  on the west lawn of the US Capitol on Wednesday. He told his friends he was going to do this.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (NP (NP (NNP Douglas) (NNP Mark) (NNP Hughes)) (, ,) (NP (NP (DT a) (NN mailman)) (PP (IN for) (NP (DT the) (NNP United) (NNPS States)))) (, ,)) (VP (VBD landed) (NP (PRP$ his)) (PP (IN on) (NP (NP (DT the) (NN west) (NN lawn)) (PP (IN of) (NP (DT the) (NNP US) (NNP Capitol))))) (PP (IN on) (NP (NNP Wednesday)))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150419" id="2073872" ><text>I
On Friday a car bomb, claimed by Islamic State of Iraq and Syria (ISIS), killed, by varying reports, at least three people and injured at least five others, possibly including a US national, outside of the United States Consulate in , Iraq. According to the  there were no injuries to consulate personnel.  According to police, following a small improvised explosion, a car approached the consulate, but exploded short of the consulate when fired on by security personnel. They said the explosives seem to have been triggered by the people inside the car, not the gunfire.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (PP (PP (IN On) (NP (NNP Friday))) (NP (NP (DT a) (NN car) (NN bomb)) (, ,) (VP (VBN claimed) (PP (IN by) (ADJP (JJ Islamic) (S (VP (NN State) (PP (IN of) (NP (NP (NNP Iraq)) (CC and) (NP (NNP Syria) (PRN (-LRB- -LRB-) (NP (NNP ISIS)) (-RRB- -RRB-))) (, ,) (VBN killed) (, ,))) (PP (IN by) (NP (VBG varying) (NNS reports))) (, ,) (NP (NP (QP (IN at) (JJS least) (CD three)) (NNS people)) (CC and) (VP (VBN injured) (NP (QP (IN at) (JJS least) (CD five)) (NNS others)))) (, ,) (S (VP (ADVP (RB possibly)) (VBG including) (NP (DT a) (NNP US) (ADJP (JJ national))))) (, ,) (PP (IN outside) (PP (IN of) (NP (DT the) (NNP United) (NNPS States) (NNP Consulate)))) (FRAG (IN in) (, ,) (NP (NNP Iraq))))))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150422" id="2080226" ><text>S
A student killed a school teacher at the Instituto Joan Fuster in Barcelona, Spain on Monday.  Reports indicate the student was thirteen years old; police said he was under fourteen.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (NP (DT A) (NN student)) (VP (VBD killed) (NP (DT a) (NN school) (NN teacher)) (PP (IN at) (NP (NP (DT the) (NNP Instituto) (NNP Joan) (NNP Fuster)) (PP (IN in) (NP (NNP Barcelona))))) (, ,) (NP (NNP Spain)) (PP (IN on) (NP (NNP Monday)))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150422" id="2082005" ><text>T
In New South Wales (NSW), Australia, two men and a woman died yesterday after search-and-rescue operations failed to rescue them from  in , roughly 200  (125 ) north of the state's capital, Sydney.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (FRAG (PP (IN In) (NP (NNP New) (NNP South) (NNP Wales))) (PRN (-LRB- -LRB-) (NP (NNP NSW)) (-RRB- -RRB-)) (, ,) (NP (NP (NNP Australia)) (, ,) (NP (NP (NP (CD two) (NNS men)) (CC and) (NP (DT a) (NN woman))) (VP (VBD died) (NP (NN yesterday)) (SBAR (IN after) (S (NP (JJ search-and-rescue) (NNS operations)) (VP (VBD failed) (S (VP (TO to) (VP (VB rescue) (NP (PRP them)) (PP (IN from) (FRAG (PP (IN in) (NP (NP (, ,) (NP (QP (RB roughly) (CD 200)) (-LRB- -LRB-) (CD 125) (-RRB- -RRB-)) (NN north)) (PP (IN of) (NP (NP (DT the) (NN state) (POS 's)) (NN capital))))) (, ,) (NP (NNP Sydney))))))))))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150422" id="2082777" ><text>U
Seattle based soccer club  (S2) lost their initial two away games of the season despite having entered the road trip undefeated with three wins. First, they played the Tulsa  who won 4-;3 on Thursday. Next, S2 traveled to nearby  to battle  on Saturday but lost 2-;1.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (NP (NP (NNP Seattle) (VBN based) (NN soccer) (NN club)) (PRN (-LRB- -LRB-) (NP (NN S2)) (-RRB- -RRB-))) (VP (VBD lost) (NP (NP (PRP$ their) (JJ initial) (CD two) (RB away) (NNS games)) (PP (IN of) (NP (DT the) (NN season)))) (PP (IN despite) (S (VP (VBG having) (VP (VBN entered) (NP (DT the) (NN road) (NN trip) (JJ undefeated)) (PP (IN with) (NP (CD three) (NNS wins)))))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150430" id="2083571" ><text>H
On Friday, Eva Mozes Kor, a 81-year-old  survivor, publicly forgave and embraced 93-year-old former  guard Oskar Gr√∂ning, who is currently on trial in Germany as an accessory to 300,000 murders of Jews at Auschwitz.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (PP (IN On) (NP (NNP Friday))) (, ,) (NP (NP (NNP Eva) (NNP Mozes) (NNP Kor)) (, ,) (NP (DT a) (JJ 81-year-old) (NN survivor)) (, ,)) (VP (ADVP (RB publicly)) (VBD forgave) (CC and) (VP (VBD embraced) (NP (JJ 93-year-old) (JJ former) (NN guard) (NNP Oskar) (NNP Gr√) (CD ∂) (NN ning))) (, ,) (SBAR (WHNP (WP who)) (S (VP (VBZ is) (ADVP (RB currently)) (PP (IN on) (NP (NP (NN trial)) (PP (IN in) (NP (NNP Germany))))) (PP (IN as) (NP (NP (DT an) (NN accessory)) (PP (TO to) (NP (NP (CD 300,000) (NNS murders)) (PP (IN of) (NP (NP (NNS Jews)) (PP (IN at) (NP (NNP Auschwitz))))))))))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150424" id="2084174" ><text>P
A power outage at Japan's Fukushima 1 nuclear plant on Tuesday has seen eight water transfer pumps shut down, hindering efforts to collect leaked radioactive water before it can reach the sea.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (NP (NP (DT A) (NN power) (NN outage)) (PP (IN at) (NP (NP (NP (NNP Japan) (POS 's)) (NNP Fukushima) (CD 1) (JJ nuclear) (NN plant)) (PP (IN on) (NP (NNP Tuesday)))))) (VP (VBZ has) (VP (VBN seen) (SBAR (S (NP (CD eight) (NN water) (NN transfer) (NNS pumps)) (VP (VBD shut) (ADVP (RB down)) (, ,) (S (VP (VBG hindering) (NP (NNS efforts) (S (VP (TO to) (VP (VB collect) (VP (VBN leaked) (NP (JJ radioactive) (NN water)) (SBAR (IN before) (S (NP (PRP it)) (VP (MD can) (VP (VB reach) (NP (DT the) (NN sea)))))))))))))))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150425" id="2089569" ><text>V
]] The  volcano in Southern Chile  twice on Wednesday. It was the first major eruption of the volcano in over fifty years.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (NP (NP (-RRB- -RSB-) (-RRB- -RSB-) (NP (DT The) (NN volcano)) (PP (IN in) (NP (NNP Southern) (NNP Chile)))) (PP (ADVP (RB twice)) (IN on) (NP (NNP Wednesday))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150427" id="2092557" ><text>O
A crowd of over 10,000 people attended the  on Saturday at ,  for the 100th anniversary of the landing of  and  troops there in 1915. The solemn remembrance ceremony was held at the site of the original Gallipoli landings, now known as .  ]] The Gallipoli Campaign of the  is remembered as a failed attack in which thousands of lives were lost for little to no gain for either side. The campaign killed 45,000  and 86,000 Turkish troops.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (NP (NP (DT A) (NN crowd)) (PP (IN of) (NP (QP (IN over) (CD 10,000)) (NNS people)))) (VP (VBD attended) (NP (DT the) (PP (IN on) (NP (NNP Saturday)))) (FRAG (IN at) (, ,) (PP (IN for) (NP (NP (DT the) (JJ 100th) (NN anniversary)) (PP (IN of) (NP (NP (DT the) (NN landing)) (PP (IN of) (SINV (CC and) (NP (NP (NNS troops)) (ADVP (RB there)) (PP (IN in) (NP (CD 1915)))))))))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150501" id="2101987" ><text>T
At 12:35 am  Wednesday morning, , 31, and , 33, leaders of the so-called "" heroin drug smugglers group, were executed on the Indonesian island of .</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (SINV (PP (IN At) (NP (CD 12:35))) (VP (VBP am)) (NP (NP (NNP Wednesday) (NN morning)) (, ,) (, ,) (NP (CD 31)) (, ,) (CC and) (, ,) (NP (CD 33)) (, ,) (NP (NP (NNS leaders)) (PP (IN of) (NP (DT the) (JJ so-called) ('' '') ('' '') (NN heroin) (NN drug) (NNS smugglers) (NN group)))) (, ,)) (VP (VBD were) (VP (VBN executed) (PP (IN on) (NP (NP (DT the) (JJ Indonesian) (NN island)) (PP (IN of)))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150508" id="2108202" ><text>I
Indiana Governor  dropped his former opposition to needle exchange programs and on Tuesday signed legislation passed by lawmakers on April 29 - the last day of the state's legislative session - that would allow local health departments, municipalities, counties, or nonprofit organizations to implement needle exchange programs. The debate about the controversial programs came on the heels of an  outbreak in Southern Indiana.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (NP (NNP Indiana) (NNP Governor)) (VP (VP (VP (VBD dropped) (NP (PRP$ his) (JJ former) (NN opposition)) (PP (TO to) (NP (NN needle) (NN exchange) (NNS programs)))) (CC and) (PP (IN on) (NP (NNP Tuesday)))) (VP (VBD signed) (NP (NP (NN legislation)) (VP (VBN passed) (PP (IN by) (NP (NP (NNS lawmakers)) (PP (IN on) (NP (NP (NNP April) (CD 29)) (: -) (NP (NP (DT the) (JJ last) (NN day)) (PP (IN of) (NP (NP (DT the) (NN state) (POS 's)) (JJ legislative) (NN session))))))))))) (: -) (VP (SBAR (WHNP (WDT that)) (S (VP (MD would) (VP (VB allow) (NP (JJ local) (NN health) (NNS departments)))))) (, ,) (NP (NP (NNS municipalities)) (, ,) (NP (NNS counties)) (, ,) (CC or) (NP (NP (JJ nonprofit) (NNS organizations)) (SBAR (S (VP (TO to) (VP (VB implement) (NP (NN needle) (NN exchange) (NNS programs)))))))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150503" id="2109457" ><text>S
, the  singer recognised for memorable track "", died on Thursday at the age of 76.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (S (, ,) (NP (DT the) (NN singer)) (VP (VBD recognised) (PP (IN for) (NP (JJ memorable) (NN track)))) ('' '') ('' '')) (, ,) (VP (VBD died) (PP (IN on) (NP (NNP Thursday))) (PP (IN at) (NP (NP (DT the) (NN age)) (PP (IN of) (NP (CD 76)))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150503" id="2109647" ><text>R
The UK's  gave birth yesterday to a baby girl, and  announced, "Her Royal Highness the Duchess of Cambridge was safely delivered of a daughter at 8:34 am."  The announcement also said Catherine and the baby are "doing well."  The daughter of the royal couple was said to weigh 8 3.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (NP (DT The) (NNP UK) (POS 's)) (VP (VP (VBD gave) (NP (NN birth)) (NP (NN yesterday)) (PP (TO to) (NP (DT a) (NN baby) (NN girl)))) (, ,) (CC and) (VP (VBD announced) (, ,) (S (`` ``) (NP (PRP$ Her) (NNP Royal) (NNP Highness)) (NP (NP (DT the) (NNP Duchess)) (PP (IN of) (NP (NNP Cambridge)))) (VP (VBD was) (VP (ADVP (RB safely)) (VBN delivered) (PP (IN of) (NP (NP (DT a) (NN daughter)) (PP (IN at) (NP (CD 8:34) (RB am))))))) (. .) ('' ''))))))</parse><sentence date="20150507" id="2117049" ><text>N
On Tuesday, the New Zealand government announced the start of a public process to suggest designs for a new national flag, and determine whether their citizens would prefer a different national flag over the current one.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (PP (IN On) (NP (NNP Tuesday))) (, ,) (NP (DT the) (NNP New) (NNP Zealand) (NN government)) (VP (VP (VBD announced) (NP (NP (DT the) (NN start)) (PP (IN of) (NP (NP (DT a) (JJ public) (NN process)) (SBAR (S (VP (TO to) (VP (VB suggest) (NP (NP (NNS designs)) (PP (IN for) (NP (DT a) (JJ new) (JJ national) (NN flag)))))))))))) (, ,) (CC and) (VP (VB determine) (SBAR (IN whether) (S (NP (PRP$ their) (NNS citizens)) (VP (MD would) (VP (VB prefer) (NP (DT a) (JJ different) (JJ national) (NN flag)) (PP (IN over) (NP (DT the) (JJ current) (CD one))))))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150509" id="2120996" ><text>C
A report from   released on Wednesday said the co-pilot, Andreas Lubitz, practiced putting a plane into a controlled descent earlier in the day of the March 24 crash of , which officials allege the co-pilot caused by a controlled descent. The report was based on data from the plane's .</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (NP (NP (DT A) (NN report)) (PP (IN from) (S (VP (VBN released) (PP (IN on) (NP (NNP Wednesday))))))) (VP (VBD said) (SBAR (S (NP (NP (DT the) (NNS co-pilot)) (, ,) (NP (NNP Andreas) (NNP Lubitz)) (, ,)) (VP (VBD practiced) (S (VP (VBG putting) (NP (DT a) (NN plane)) (PP (IN into) (NP (NP (DT a) (JJ controlled) (NN descent)) (ADVP (RBR earlier) (PP (IN in) (NP (NP (DT the) (NN day)) (PP (IN of) (NP (NP (DT the) (NNP March) (CD 24) (NN crash)) (PP (IN of) (, ,)) (SBAR (WHNP (WDT which)) (S (NP (NNS officials)) (VP (VBP allege) (NP (NP (DT the) (NNS co-pilot)) (VP (VBN caused) (PP (IN by) (NP (DT a) (JJ controlled) (NN descent))))))))))))))))))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150509" id="2125560" ><text>C
David Cameron is to continue being  of the UK after his Conservative Party won a majority of seats in a general election on Thursday. Although the party led a Coalition government it formed alongside the Liberal Democrats after the previous general election in 2010, this is the first time the party has won an overall majority since 1992. ]'']</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (NP (NNP David) (NNP Cameron)) (VP (VBZ is) (S (VP (TO to) (VP (VB continue) (S (VP (VBG being) (PP (IN of) (NP (DT the) (NNP UK))))) (SBAR (IN after) (S (NP (PRP$ his) (NNP Conservative) (NNP Party)) (VP (VBD won) (NP (NP (DT a) (NN majority)) (PP (IN of) (NP (NP (NNS seats)) (PP (IN in) (NP (NP (DT a) (JJ general) (NN election)) (PP (IN on) (NP (NNP Thursday))))))))))))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150512" id="2132221" ><text>F
A  tore through much of the town of ,  late Sunday evening. Officials said over 40 people were transported to local hospitals for treatment and reportedly two people died during the storm - David Tapley, a retired , Texas police officer, and his wife.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (NP (NP (S (NP (DT A)) (VP (VBD tore) (NP (NP (RB through) (JJ much)) (PP (IN of) (NP (NP (DT the) (NN town)) (PP (IN of))))))) (, ,) (NP (JJ late) (NNP Sunday) (NN evening))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150511" id="2132251" ><text>U
Nigel Farage today reversed his decision to stand down as leader of the UK Independence Party (UKIP) after its National Executive Committee (NEC) rejected his resignation. Farage had previously said he would stand down as leader because he did not win the  seat in last week's UK general election.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (NP (NNP Nigel) (NNP Farage)) (NP (NN today)) (VP (VBD reversed) (NP (PRP$ his) (NN decision) (S (VP (TO to) (VP (VB stand) (ADVP (RP down)) (PP (IN as) (NP (NP (NP (NN leader)) (PP (IN of) (NP (DT the) (NNP UK) (NNP Independence) (NNP Party)))) (PRN (-LRB- -LRB-) (NP (NNP UKIP)) (-RRB- -RRB-)))) (SBAR (IN after) (S (NP (NP (PRP$ its) (NNP National) (NNP Executive) (NNP Committee)) (PRN (-LRB- -LRB-) (NP (NNP NEC)) (-RRB- -RRB-))) (VP (VBD rejected) (NP (PRP$ his) (NN resignation)))))))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150518" id="2144299" ><text>O
On Friday, fishermen rescued over 700 asylum seekers whose boat sank, and the Indonesian Navy reportedly saved 200 more after they were found swimming along the coast of , Indonesia.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (PP (IN On) (NP (NNP Friday))) (, ,) (NP (NNS fishermen)) (VP (VBD rescued) (SBAR (S (NP (QP (IN over) (CD 700)) (NN asylum) (NNS seekers)) (WHNP (WHNP (WP$ whose) (NN boat)) (VP (VBD sank))) (NP (, ,) (CC and) (DT the) (JJ Indonesian) (NNP Navy)) (ADVP (RB reportedly)) (VP (VBD saved) (NP (CD 200) (JJR more)) (SBAR (IN after) (S (NP (PRP they)) (VP (VBD were) (VP (VBN found) (S (VP (VBG swimming) (FRAG (IN along) (NP (DT the) (NN coast)) (IN of) (, ,) (NP (NNP Indonesia))))))))))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150517" id="2144646" ><text>J
Jim Murphy yesterday announced he intends to stand down as Scottish Labour Party leader next month, after narrowly surviving a  vote. Murphy said he will present a list of suggested reforms to be made to the party, including changing the system for electing party leader to , upon offering his resignation at the next meeting of its national executive in June. Murphy also said he will not stand for the Scottish Parliament  and will "do something else".</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (NP (NNP Jim) (NNP Murphy)) (NP (NN yesterday)) (VP (VBD announced) (SBAR (S (NP (PRP he)) (VP (VBZ intends) (S (VP (TO to) (VP (VB stand) (PRT (RP down)) (PP (IN as) (NP (JJ Scottish) (NNP Labour) (NNP Party) (NN leader))) (NP (JJ next) (NN month))))) (, ,) (PP (IN after) (S (VP (ADVP (RB narrowly)) (VBG surviving) (NP (DT a) (NN vote))))))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150520" id="2148252" ><text>F
On Sunday, at  in Madrid, Spain, F.C. Barcelona association football club won the Spanish  title. The team defeated Atl√©tico Madrid 1-;0 to clinch the title for the 23rd time.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (PP (IN On) (NP (NNP Sunday))) (, ,) (IN at) (PP (IN in) (NP (NP (NNP Madrid)) (, ,) (NP (NNP Spain)) (, ,))) (NP (NNP F.C.) (NNP Barcelona) (NN association) (NN football) (NN club)) (VP (VBD won) (NP (DT the) (JJ Spanish) (NN title))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150518" id="2150189" ><text>N
Nine people are dead and eighteen injured after a shootout among alleged rival biker gangs broke out inside a sports bar in Texas yesterday.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (NP (CD Nine) (NNS people)) (VP (VBP are) (ADJP (JJ dead) (CC and) (NP (CD eighteen) (VBN injured))) (SBAR (IN after) (S (NP (NP (DT a) (NN shootout)) (PP (IN among) (NP (JJ alleged) (JJ rival) (NN biker) (NNS gangs)))) (VP (VBD broke) (PRT (RP out)) (PP (IN inside) (NP (NP (DT a) (NNS sports) (NN bar)) (PP (IN in) (NP (NNP Texas))))) (NP (NN yesterday)))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150518" id="2150662" ><text>F
On Saturday, French Prime Minister  stated his opposition to the European Commission's quota system for distributing  amongst member countries of the European Union (EU).</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (PP (IN On) (NP (NNP Saturday))) (, ,) (NP (NNP French) (NNP Prime) (NNP Minister)) (VP (VBD stated) (NP (NP (PRP$ his) (NN opposition)) (PP (TO to) (NP (NP (NP (DT the) (JJ European) (NNP Commission) (POS 's)) (NN quota) (NN system)) (PP (IN for) (S (VP (VBG distributing) (PP (IN amongst) (NP (NP (NN member) (NNS countries)) (PP (IN of) (NP (DT the) (NNP European) (NNP Union)))))))) (PRN (-LRB- -LRB-) (NP (NNP EU)) (-RRB- -RRB-)))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150521" id="2153130" ><text>Y
Former Thai prime minister  has begun her trial in Bangkok on Tuesday for alleged negligence in a rice subsidy scheme. If convicted she could face up to ten years in jail.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (NP (JJ Former) (NNP Thai) (JJ prime) (NN minister)) (VP (VBZ has) (VP (VBN begun) (NP (NP (PRP$ her) (NN trial)) (PP (IN in) (NP (NNP Bangkok))) (PP (IN on) (NP (NNP Tuesday)))) (PP (IN for) (NP (NP (JJ alleged) (NN negligence)) (PP (IN in) (NP (DT a) (NN rice) (NN subsidy) (NN scheme))))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150523" id="2158423" ><text>6
An earthquake hit close to the , in the early hours of Thursday morning. It was about 184 kilometres from Lata and 487 kilometres from the capital Honiara.  The US Geological Survey has stated that Tsunami warnings are yet to be released and that no major damage occurred.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (NP (DT An) (NN earthquake)) (VP (VBD hit) (ADVP (RB close) (PP (TO to) (NP (DT the)))) (, ,) (PP (IN in) (NP (NP (DT the) (JJ early) (NNS hours)) (PP (IN of) (NP (NNP Thursday) (NN morning)))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150524" id="2166209" ><text>T
from London, United Kingdom]  has set a new  record with her music video Bad Blood getting 20.1 million views in 24 hours this past week. The artist took the title from  who had 19.6 million views for Anaconda in August 2014.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (PP (IN from) (NP (NP (NNP London)) (, ,) (NP (NNP United) (NNP Kingdom)))) (-RRB- -RSB-) (VP (VBZ has) (VP (VBN set) (NP (DT a) (JJ new) (NN record)) (PP (IN with) (S (NP (PRP$ her) (NN music) (NN video) (NNP Bad) (NNP Blood)) (VP (VBG getting) (NP (QP (CD 20.1) (CD million)) (NNS views)) (PP (IN in) (NP (CD 24) (NNS hours))) (NP (DT this) (JJ past) (NN week))))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150524" id="2166682" ><text>I
by public vote on Friday legalised . This was the first time a country legalized same-sex marriage by popular vote.  The historic referendum resulted in a landslide sixty percent "yes".</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (PP (IN by) (NP (JJ public) (NN vote))) (PP (IN on) (NP (NNP Friday))) (VP (VBD legalised)) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150527" id="2171616" ><text>T
Recently, record breaking rainfall has doled out severe destruction over much of the state of Texas, . The state's governor called the effects of the storms "absolutely devastating". At least two people died over the weekend, while twelve more were reported missing.   Various rainfall records have been broken all over the state in recent days. On Sunday alone, over three inches of rain fell in the city of Dallas. In , one official described the flooding as "the largest flood in the history of this region" - at least 350 homes there were destroyed and an additional 1,000 homes suffered damage.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (ADVP (RB Recently)) (, ,) (NP (NP (NN record)) (VP (VBG breaking) (NP (NNS rainfall)))) (VP (VBZ has) (VP (VBN doled) (PRT (RP out)) (NP (NP (JJ severe) (NN destruction)) (PP (IN over) (NP (NP (JJ much)) (PP (IN of) (NP (NP (DT the) (NN state)) (PP (IN of) (NP (NNP Texas)))))))) (, ,))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150528" id="2171764" ><text>J
has agreed to reconsider the  (GST) on tampons and other hygiene products after being confronted about the issue on  Monday night. Mr Hockey was responding to a question from  Subeta Vimalarajah.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (VP (VBZ has) (VP (VBN agreed) (S (VP (TO to) (VP (VB reconsider) (NP (NP (DT the) (PRN (-LRB- -LRB-) (NP (NN GST)) (-RRB- -RRB-))) (PP (IN on) (NP (NP (NNS tampons)) (CC and) (NP (JJ other) (NN hygiene) (NNS products))))) (PP (IN after) (S (VP (VBG being) (VP (VBN confronted) (PP (IN about) (NP (DT the) (NN issue))) (PP (IN on) (NP (NNP Monday) (NN night)))))))))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150528" id="2171912" ><text>W
Police in Western Australia revealed Monday they have reason to believe 59-year-old Francis John Wark was involved in the alleged murder of Hayley Marie Dodd. A  was subsequently issued for his arrest, and it is likely that he will be charged.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (NP (NP (NNS Police)) (PP (IN in) (NP (NNP Western) (NNP Australia)))) (VP (VBD revealed) (NP (NNP Monday)) (SBAR (S (NP (PRP they)) (VP (VBP have) (NP (NN reason) (S (VP (TO to) (VP (VB believe) (SBAR (S (NP (JJ 59-year-old) (NNP Francis) (NNP John) (NNP Wark)) (VP (VBD was) (VP (VBN involved) (PP (IN in) (NP (NP (DT the) (JJ alleged) (NN murder)) (PP (IN of) (NP (NNP Hayley) (NNP Marie) (NNP Dodd))))))))))))))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150528" id="2171982" ><text>B
Two daughters of blues legend  are claiming on Monday that he was poisoned by business manager LaVerne Toney and personal assistant Myron Johnson. The allegations were made by daughters Karen Williams and Patty King in affidavits provided by their lawyer to the Associated Press.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (NP (NP (CD Two) (NNS daughters)) (PP (IN of) (NP (NNS blues) (NN legend)))) (VP (VBP are) (VP (VBG claiming) (PP (IN on) (NP (NNP Monday))) (SBAR (IN that) (S (NP (PRP he)) (VP (VBD was) (VP (VBN poisoned) (PP (IN by) (NP (NP (NN business) (NN manager) (NNP LaVerne) (NNP Toney)) (CC and) (NP (JJ personal) (NN assistant) (NNP Myron) (NNP Johnson)))))))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150527" id="2175529" ><text>C
]] Yesterday, 's  proposed his government might strip individuals of their Australian citizenship if authorities consider them involved in terrorist activity.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (NP (-RRB- -RSB-) (-RRB- -RSB-) (NN Yesterday)) (, ,) (VP (POS 's) (VP (VBN proposed) (SBAR (S (NP (PRP$ his) (NN government)) (VP (MD might) (VP (VB strip) (NP (NP (NNS individuals)) (PP (IN of) (NP (PRP$ their) (JJ Australian) (NN citizenship)))) (SBAR (IN if) (S (NP (NNS authorities)) (VP (VBP consider) (S (NP (PRP them)) (VP (VBN involved) (PP (IN in) (NP (JJ terrorist) (NN activity)))))))))))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150530" id="2180975" ><text>N
Australian , 43, previously convicted of rape and murder, has been sentenced on Thursday to a further 18 years in prison for three more rapes.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (NP (NP (JJ Australian) (, ,) (NP (CD 43)) (, ,)) (VP (VP (ADVP (RB previously)) (VBN convicted) (PP (IN of) (NP (NN rape) (CC and) (NN murder)))) (, ,) (VP (VBZ has) (VP (VBN been) (VP (VBN sentenced) (PP (IN on) (NP (NNP Thursday))) (PP (TO to) (NP (NP (NP (DT a) (JJ further) (CD 18) (NNS years)) (PP (IN in) (NP (NN prison)))) (PP (IN for) (NP (CD three) (JJR more) (NNS rapes))))))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150601" id="2187955" ><text>K
U.S. Secretary of State John Kerry had a cycling accident yesterday and as a result has broken his right leg. The accident happened near , France; reportedly he may have hit a curb.  Kerry was in  on Saturday for talks with the Iranian Foreign Minister, , on the Iranian nuclear program. As a result of the accident Kerry has canceled his official trips, including an international conference on  (ISIS).</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (NP (NAC (NNP U.S.) (NNP Secretary) (PP (IN of) (NP (NNP State)))) (NNP John) (NNP Kerry)) (VP (VP (VBD had) (NP (DT a) (NN cycling) (NN accident)) (NP (NN yesterday))) (CC and) (SBAR (IN as) (S (NP (DT a) (NN result)) (VP (VBZ has) (VP (VBN broken) (NP (PRP$ his) (JJ right) (NN leg))))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150602" id="2189492" ><text>B
US Vice President Joe Biden's son  died of  on Saturday.  He was 46.  After being diagnosed less than two years ago, Beau underwent treatment and was considered recovered, but was recently admitted to  in ,  due to return of the cancer.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (NP (NP (NNP US) (NNP Vice) (NNP President) (NNP Joe) (NNP Biden) (POS 's)) (NN son)) (VP (VBD died) (PP (IN of) (PP (IN on) (NP (NNP Saturday))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150604" id="2194780" ><text>C
, British former  who once led the Liberal Democrats, has died at age 55. He was found dead on Monday at his home in , Scotland by his partner, Carole Macdonald.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (NP (, ,) (JJ British) (JJ former) (SBAR (WHNP (WP who)) (S (ADVP (RB once)) (VP (VBD led) (NP (DT the) (JJ Liberal) (NNPS Democrats)))))) (, ,) (VP (VBZ has) (VP (VBN died) (PP (IN at) (NP (NN age) (CD 55))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150605" id="2199048" ><text>A
Australian business tycoon  died today after complications from . He was 77.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (NP (JJ Australian) (NN business) (NN tycoon)) (VP (VBD died) (NP (NN today)) (PP (IN after) (NP (NP (NNS complications)) (PP (IN from))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150606" id="2200669" ><text>M
, former UK Liberal Democrats leader, died of a major haemorrhage linked to his , his family announced in a statement yesterday. Kennedy, a Scottish former , died unexpectedly on Monday at the age of 55.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (NP (, ,) (JJ former) (NNP UK) (NNP Liberal) (NNPS Democrats) (NN leader)) (, ,) (VP (VBD died) (PP (IN of) (NP (NP (DT a) (JJ major) (NN haemorrhage)) (VP (VBN linked) (PP (TO to) (NP (NP (PRP$ his)) (, ,) (NP (PRP$ his) (NN family)) (VP (VBD announced) (PP (IN in) (NP (DT a) (NN statement))) (NP (NN yesterday))))))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150611" id="2211051" ><text>1
Authorities arrested a 16-year-old girl on Tuesday on an attempted murder charge after the stabbing of another 16-year-old girl, Monica Hawkins, outside the  shopping centre in Melbourne, Australia.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (NP (NNP Authorities)) (VP (VBD arrested) (NP (NP (DT a) (JJ 16-year-old) (NN girl)) (PP (IN on) (NP (NNP Tuesday)))) (PP (IN on) (NP (NP (DT an) (VBN attempted) (NN murder) (NN charge)) (PP (IN after) (NP (NP (DT the) (VBG stabbing)) (PP (IN of) (NP (NP (DT another) (JJ 16-year-old) (NN girl)) (, ,) (NP (NNP Monica) (NNP Hawkins)) (, ,))) (PP (IN outside) (NP (NP (DT the) (NN shopping) (NN centre)) (PP (IN in) (NP (NNP Melbourne) (, ,) (NNP Australia)))))))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150610" id="2212073" ><text>B
Long-time boxing referee  has died at the age of 86. Cappuccino, who died in , Pennsylvania on Monday, was suffering from . He started his career in the 1950s and officiated on some of the most famous fights in boxing history; these included 94 world championship fights.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (NP (JJ Long-time) (NN boxing) (NN referee)) (VP (VBZ has) (VP (VBN died) (PP (IN at) (NP (NP (DT the) (NN age)) (PP (IN of) (NP (CD 86))))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150613" id="2216681" ><text>E
Famed English actor, singer and author  died last Sunday morning in  aged 93, after being admitted to  for heart failure and respiratory problems. News of his death only became public on Thursday, as his wife of 54 years, Birgit Kr√∏ncke Lee, wished first to inform friends and family.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (NP (NP (JJ Famed) (JJ English) (NN actor)) (, ,) (NP (NN singer)) (CC and) (NP (NN author))) (VP (VBD died) (NP (JJ last) (NNP Sunday) (NN morning)) (PP (IN in) (NP (JJ aged) (CD 93))) (, ,) (PP (IN after) (S (VP (VBG being) (VP (VBN admitted) (PP (TO to)))))) (PP (PP (IN for) (NP (NN heart) (NN failure))) (CC and) (NP (JJ respiratory) (NNS problems)))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150620" id="2239285" ><text>D
As of today, as many as 84 people are reported dead since Wednesday after drinking toxic homemade  sold in a slum in  in northern Mumbai. More than twenty others are reported admitted to hospital for alcohol poisoning.  Police said five people have been arrested for the transport and sale of the alcohol with three men ages 30 to 50 taken into police custody on Thursday night, and eight police suspended for failing to prevent the incident.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (PP (IN As) (PP (IN of) (NP (NN today)))) (, ,) (NP (QP (IN as) (JJ many) (IN as) (CD 84)) (NNS people)) (VP (VBP are) (VP (VBN reported) (ADJP (JJ dead)) (PP (IN since) (NP (NNP Wednesday))) (PP (IN after) (S (VP (VBG drinking) (NP (NP (JJ toxic) (NN homemade)) (VP (VBN sold) (PP (IN in) (NP (NP (DT a) (NN slum)) (PP (IN in) (PP (IN in) (NP (JJ northern) (NNP Mumbai))))))))))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150626" id="2257814" ><text>F
, Scottish Conservative Party leader from 2005 to 2011, has announced she will stand down as an  at the . Goldie, who has been an MSP for the  (previously ) electoral region since the Scottish Parliament's formation in 1999, said she intends to focus on her role in the , where she has been a  since 2013.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (NP (NP (, ,) (JJ Scottish) (NNP Conservative) (NNP Party) (NN leader)) (PP (PP (IN from) (NP (CD 2005))) (PP (TO to) (NP (CD 2011))))) (, ,) (VP (VBZ has) (VP (VBN announced) (SBAR (S (NP (PRP she)) (VP (MD will) (VP (VB stand) (PRT (RP down)) (PP (IN as) (PP (DT an) (IN at) (DT the))))))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150629" id="2262078" ><text>A
On Friday, Argentina defeated Colombia in the third quarter- final of the  ], en, Spanish language, America Cup] which was held in  stadium in , Chile. Argentina defeated Colombia 5-;4 on .</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (PP (IN On) (NP (NNP Friday))) (, ,) (NP (NNP Argentina)) (VP (VBD defeated) (NP (NNP Colombia)) (PP (IN in) (NP (DT the) (JJ third) (NN quarter))) (: -) (ADJP (JJ final) (PP (IN of) (NP (DT the) (-RRB- -RSB-)))) (, ,) (SBAR (IN en) (, ,) (PRN (NP (NP (JJ Spanish) (NN language)) (, ,) (NP (NNP America) (NNP Cup))) (-RRB- -RSB-)) (SBAR (WHNP (WDT which)) (S (VP (VBD was) (VP (VBN held) (PP (IN in) (NP (NP (NN stadium)) (PP (IN in) (NP (, ,) (NNP Chile))))))))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150628" id="2262768" ><text>U
On Friday, the United States Supreme Court declared same-sex marriage legal in all fifty US states. More than 30 states already permitted gay marriage. The Supreme Court ruled by a five-to-four vote that bans on same-sex marriage were not constitutional. The majority decision was delivered by .</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (PP (IN On) (NP (NNP Friday))) (, ,) (NP (DT the) (NNP United) (NNPS States) (NNP Supreme) (NNP Court)) (VP (VBD declared) (NP (NP (JJ same-sex) (NN marriage)) (ADJP (JJ legal) (PP (IN in) (NP (DT all) (CD fifty) (NNP US) (NNS states)))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150702" id="2263401" ><text>F
On Saturday, Francesc Sol√© reached the finish in  as winner of the   after 170  over an altitude range of 13,500  and 31:09 hours.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (PP (IN On) (NP (NNP Saturday))) (, ,) (NP (NNP Francesc) (NNP Sol√) (CD ©)) (VP (VBD reached) (NP (DT the) (NN finish)) (PP (IN in) (PP (IN as) (NP (NP (NN winner)) (PP (IN of) (NP (DT the)))))) (PP (IN after) (NP (NP (CD 170)) (PP (IN over) (NP (NP (NP (DT an) (NN altitude) (NN range)) (PP (IN of) (NP (CD 13,500)))) (CC and) (NP (CD 31:09) (NNS hours))))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150704" id="2273120" ><text>C
On Tuesday, an   crashed in the city of , Indonesia. All 122 people on board were killed as well as people on the ground in the city in , according to North Sumatra police Major A. Tarigan. Officials said the plane exploded on impact into a big fireball. ]] The military said the plane took off at 12:08 pm  (0508 ) and crashed five  away a couple of minutes later. According to Agus Supriatna, chief of the Air Force, the pilot reported technical problems and requested return to base. The aircraft was en route from  to .</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (FRAG (PP (IN On) (NP (NNP Tuesday))) (, ,) (NP (DT an) (VP (VBN crashed) (PP (IN in) (FRAG (NP (DT the) (NN city)) (IN of) (, ,) (NP (NNP Indonesia)))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150702" id="2274227" ><text>A
On Tuesday, Argentina defeated Paraguay 6-;1 in the second semi-final of the  ], en, Spanish language, America Cup] which was held in  city of Chile to reach the finals.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (PP (IN On) (NP (NNP Tuesday))) (, ,) (NP (NNP Argentina)) (VP (VBD defeated) (NP (NNP Paraguay) (CD 6)) (: -) (: ;) (S (NP (NP (NP (CD 1)) (PP (IN in) (NP (NP (DT the) (JJ second) (NN semi-final)) (PP (IN of) (NP (DT the) (-RRB- -RSB-)))))) (, ,) (NP (IN en)) (, ,) (NP (JJ Spanish) (NN language)) (, ,) (NP (NNP America) (NNP Cup))) (NP (NP (-RRB- -RSB-)) (SBAR (WHNP (WDT which)) (S (VP (VBD was) (VP (VBN held) (PP (IN in) (NP (NP (NN city)) (PP (IN of) (NP (NNP Chile))))) (S (VP (TO to) (VP (VB reach) (NP (DT the) (NNS finals)))))))))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150704" id="2283582" ><text>P
Yesterday, Peru defeated Paraguay 2-;0 in the  of the  ], en, Spanish language, America Cup], which was held in  stadium in  city of Chile, and won a bronze medal.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (NP (NN Yesterday)) (, ,) (NP (NNP Peru)) (VP (VBD defeated) (NP (NNP Paraguay)) (FRAG (LST (LS 2) (: -)) (: ;) (FRAG (NP (NP (QP (CD 0) (IN in) (DT the))) (PP (IN of) (NP (DT the) (-RRB- -RSB-)))) (, ,) (NP (NP (NP (IN en) (, ,) (JJ Spanish) (NN language)) (, ,) (NP (NNP America) (NNP Cup)) (-RRB- -RSB-) (, ,) (SBAR (WHNP (WDT which)) (S (VP (VBD was) (VP (VBN held) (PP (IN in) (NP (NP (NN stadium)) (PP (IN in) (NP (NP (NN city)) (PP (IN of) (NP (NNP Chile))))))))))) (, ,)) (CC and) (VP (VBD won) (NP (DT a) (NN bronze) (NN medal))))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150706" id="2286596" ><text>C
On Saturday, host nation  defeated  4-;1 over penalties in the  , which was held in  located in the Chilean city of , to clinch the title for the very first time.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (S (PP (IN On) (NP (NNP Saturday))) (, ,) (NP (NN host) (NN nation)) (VP (VBD defeated) (LST (LS 4) (: -))) (: ;)) (ADJP (CD 1) (PP (IN over) (NP (NP (NNS penalties)) (PP (IN in) (NP (DT the) (, ,) (SBAR (WHNP (WDT which)) (S (VP (VBD was) (VP (VBN held) (PP (IN in) (ADJP (JJ located) (PP (IN in) (NP (NP (DT the) (JJ Chilean) (NN city)) (PP (IN of)))))))))) (, ,))))) (S (VP (TO to) (VP (VB clinch) (NP (DT the) (NN title)) (PP (IN for) (NP (DT the) (ADJP (RB very) (JJ first)) (NN time))))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150707" id="2286747" ><text>E
On Saturday,  defeated two-time world champion  by 1-;0 in the  in the  , which was held in  in ,  in , and won the bronze medal.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (PP (IN On) (NP (NNP Saturday))) (, ,) (VP (VBD defeated) (NP (JJ two-time) (NN world) (NN champion)) (PP (IN by) (S (LST (LS 1) (: -)) (: ;) (NP (CD 0) (PP (IN in) (NP (DT the) (PP (IN in) (NP (NP (DT the)) (, ,) (SBAR (WHNP (WDT which)) (S (VP (VBD was) (VP (VBN held) (ADVP (IN in)) (S (IN in) (, ,) (IN in) (, ,) (CC and) (VP (VBD won) (NP (DT the) (NN bronze) (NN medal)))))))))))))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150715" id="2306835" ><text>D
On Sunday,  defeated seven-time champion  7‚Äì6, 6‚Äì7, 6‚Äì4, 6‚Äì3 to win the  men's singles, which is overall his third Wimbledon trophy of his career. Djokovic, who is ranked world number one in men's tennis, has now won a total of nine ¬†titles.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (PP (IN On) (NP (NNP Sunday))) (, ,) (VP (VBD defeated) (NP (JJ seven-time) (NN champion)) (NP (ADJP (RB 7‚) ($ $) (`` ``) (NP (CD 6))) (, ,) (NP (NP (NP (QP (CD 6‚) ($ $) (`` ``) (CD 7))) (, ,) (NP (CD 6‚) ($ $) (`` ``) (CD 4)) (, ,)) (NP (CD 6‚)) (NP (VP ($ $) (`` ``) (VP (CD 3) (S (VP (TO to) (VP (VB win) (NP (NP (NP (DT the) (NNS men) (POS 's)) (NNS singles)) (, ,) (SBAR (WHNP (WDT which)) (S (VP (VBZ is) (NP (NP (JJ overall) (PRP$ his) (JJ third) (NNP Wimbledon) (NN trophy)) (PP (IN of) (NP (PRP$ his) (NN career))))))))))))))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150719" id="2312656" ><text>F
]] French Formula One (F1) driver  died on Friday night at age 25, nine months after his serious accident at the . News of his death was announced by his family the following morning:</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (NP (-RRB- -RSB-) (-RRB- -RSB-) (JJ French) (NNP Formula) (CD One) (-LRB- -LRB-) (NN F1) (-RRB- -RRB-) (NN driver)) (VP (VBD died) (PP (IN on) (NP (NNP Friday) (NN night))) (PP (IN at) (NP (NN age) (CD 25))) (, ,) (PP (NP (CD nine) (NNS months)) (IN after) (NP (NP (PRP$ his) (JJ serious) (NN accident)) (PP (IN at) (NP (DT the)))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150725" id="2324200" ><text>U
In Queensland's Sunshine Coast Rugby Union, University defeated Toads 45 points to 17 at , Australia this afternoon. They opened the scoring after 18 minutes with an .</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (PP (IN In) (NP (NP (NNP Queensland) (POS 's)) (NNP Sunshine) (NNP Coast) (NNP Rugby) (NNP Union))) (, ,) (NP (NNP University)) (VP (VBD defeated) (NP (NNP Toads)) (NP (CD 45) (NNS points)) (PP (TO to) (NP (CD 17))) (S (IN at) (, ,) (S (NP (NNP Australia)) (NP (DT this) (NN afternoon))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150728" id="2328072" ><text>F
Yesterday, former Indian president  died at the age of 83 after collapsing at about 6:30 p.m.  (0000 today ) while delivering a speech about Livable Planet Earth at the , in , . Abdul Kalam was taken to Bethany Hospital's  and was declared dead about an hour and a half later.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (NP (NN Yesterday)) (, ,) (NP (JJ former) (JJ Indian) (NN president)) (VP (VBD died) (PP (IN at) (NP (NP (DT the) (NN age)) (PP (IN of) (NP (CD 83))))) (PP (IN after) (S (VP (VBG collapsing) (PP (IN at) (NP (NP (IN about) (CD 6:30) (NN p.m.)) (PRN (-LRB- -LRB-) (NP (QP (CD 0000)) (NN today)) (-RRB- -RRB-)))) (SBAR (IN while) (S (VP (VBG delivering) (NP (NP (DT a) (NN speech)) (PP (IN about) (NP (NNP Livable) (NN Planet) (NNP Earth)))) (PP (IN at) (NP (DT the) (, ,))) (PP (IN in) (, ,))))))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150802" id="2334812" ><text>L
In the past few days in , several municipalities have started asking religious schools to pay taxes for property and local services, despite the resistance of the .</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (FRAG (PP (IN In) (NP (DT the) (JJ past) (JJ few) (NNS days))) (SBAR (IN in) (, ,) (S (NP (JJ several) (NNS municipalities)) (VP (VBP have) (VP (VBN started) (S (VP (VBG asking) (S (NP (JJ religious) (NNS schools)) (VP (TO to) (VP (VB pay) (NP (NNS taxes)) (PP (IN for) (NP (NN property) (CC and) (JJ local) (NNS services))) (, ,) (PP (IN despite) (NP (NP (DT the) (NN resistance)) (PP (IN of) (NP (DT the)))))))))))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150804" id="2339941" ><text>A
On Sunday, London-based football club Arsenal, winners of the , defeated   Champions Chelsea 1-;0 in the   which was played in the .  The match saw only two , to one player from each club in the second half. Though Arsenal had lesser possession of the ball and fewer shots, they had more shots on target. A total of 23 fouls were committed.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (S (PP (IN On) (NP (NNP Sunday))) (, ,) (NP (NP (JJ London-based) (NN football) (NN club) (NN Arsenal)) (, ,) (NP (NP (NNS winners)) (PP (IN of) (NP (DT the)))) (, ,)) (VP (VBD defeated) (NP (NNPS Champions) (NNP Chelsea) (LS 1) (: -))) (: ;)) (NP (CD 0) (PP (IN in) (NP (DT the) (SBAR (WHNP (WDT which)) (S (VP (VBD was) (VP (VBN played) (PP (IN in) (NP (DT the)))))))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150805" id="2342319" ><text>U
U.S. Republican Party  candidate , former commissioner of the  (IRS), filed a complaint on Monday with the  (FEC) to challenge his exclusion from Thursday's first  Republican Party presidential debate. Everson argues his exclusion violates Title 11 of the  in that debate hosts must not "structure the debates to promote or advance one candidate over another", and must "use pre-established objective criteria to determine which candidates may participate in a debate."  Everson served as Commissioner of the IRS from 2003 to 2007, during the  administration. After his departure, he briefly served as CEO of the , worked in the cabinet of Indiana  , and worked for the tax consulting firm . He announced his candidacy this past March with a sixteen-page open letter in which he outlined the six pillars of his campaign: amnesty for , reinstatement of the , a promise to serve only a single presidential term, and calls for tax reform, deficit reduction, and corporate responsibility.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (NP (NP (NNP U.S.) (NNP Republican) (NNP Party) (NN candidate)) (, ,) (NP (NP (JJ former) (NN commissioner)) (PP (IN of) (NP (DT the) (PRN (-LRB- -LRB-) (NP (NNP IRS)) (-RRB- -RRB-))))) (, ,)) (VP (VBD filed) (NP (DT a) (NN complaint)) (PP (IN on) (NP (NNP Monday))) (PP (IN with) (NP (DT the) (PRN (-LRB- -LRB-) (NP (NN FEC)) (-RRB- -RRB-)))) (S (VP (TO to) (VP (VB challenge) (NP (PRP$ his) (NN exclusion)) (PP (IN from) (NP (NP (NNP Thursday) (POS 's)) (JJ first) (NNP Republican) (NNP Party) (JJ presidential) (NN debate))))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150807" id="2347955" ><text>F
]] On Wednesday, -based football club FC Barcelona defeated -based   football club  3-;0 in the 2015  played in  stadium, .</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (-RRB- -RSB-) (S (-RRB- -RSB-) (PP (IN On) (NP (NNP Wednesday))) (, ,) (: -) (NP (VBN based) (NN football) (NN club) (NN FC) (NNP Barcelona)) (VP (VBD defeated) (: -) (NP (NP (VBN based) (NN football) (NN club) (CD 3) (: -)) (: ;) (NP (NP (CD 0)) (PP (IN in) (NP (NP (DT the) (CD 2015)) (VP (VBN played) (PP (IN in) (NP (NN stadium))))))) (, ,)))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150809" id="2348872" ><text>S
]] Authorities are investigating what's left of debris believed to belong to a plane, that washed ashore several small islands in the . The investigation began as a result of photos of the debris being uploaded to the social networking  . Some of the debris is reported to have washed ashore as early as May 31 and was found on a beach owned by the Banyan Tree Vabbinfaru resort, located in . In the past few days, several other pieces of debris were recovered on at least three other islands. Authorities are trying to determine if it may be part of  (MH370). Last week, a piece of a wing known as a , reported to be from MH370, was found washed ashore on  Island.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (NP (-RRB- -RSB-) (-RRB- -RSB-) (NNS Authorities)) (VP (VBP are) (VP (VBG investigating) (SBAR (WHNP (WP what)) (S (VP (VBZ 's) (NP (NP (NN left)) (PP (IN of) (NP (NP (NN debris)) (VP (VBN believed) (S (VP (TO to) (VP (VB belong) (PP (TO to) (NP (NP (DT a) (NN plane)) (, ,) (SBAR (WHNP (WDT that)) (S (VP (VBD washed) (ADVP (RB ashore)) (NP (NP (JJ several) (JJ small) (NNS islands)) (PP (IN in) (NP (DT the))))))))))))))))))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150810" id="2351865" ><text>M
On Saturday, -based football club  defeated -based football club  1-;0 in  stadium in .</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (PP (IN On) (NP (NNP Saturday))) (, ,) (: -) (S (VP (VBN based) (VP (NN football) (S (VP (NN club) (VP (VBD defeated) (: -) (S (VP (VBN based) (VP (NN football) (NP (NN club) (CD 1) (: -) (: ;) (NP (NP (CD 0)) (PP (IN in) (NP (NP (NN stadium)) (PP (IN in))))))))))))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150813" id="2353999" ><text>E
Saturday night, police in Houston, Texas, United States, discovered eight people killed in a home.  Six of the victims were children.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (FRAG (NP (NNP Saturday) (NN night)) (, ,) (NP (NP (NP (NN police)) (PP (IN in) (NP (NNP Houston)))) (, ,) (NP (NNP Texas)) (, ,) (NP (NNP United) (NNPS States)) (, ,) (VP (VBN discovered) (NP (NP (CD eight) (NNS people)) (VP (VBN killed) (PP (IN in) (NP (DT a) (NN home))))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150810" id="2356121" ><text>M
After published reports stated suspected plane debris washed up on several  islands,  has stated it will send a team of investigators to examine it. Investigators are to try to determine if the debris came from a plane before taking any further action.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (SBAR (IN After) (S (NP (VBN published) (NNS reports)) (VP (VBD stated) (NP (NP (VBN suspected) (NN plane) (NN debris)) (VP (VBN washed) (PRT (RP up)) (PP (IN on) (NP (JJ several) (NNS islands)))))))) (, ,) (VP (VBZ has) (VP (VBN stated) (SBAR (S (NP (PRP it)) (VP (MD will) (VP (VB send) (NP (NP (DT a) (NN team)) (PP (IN of) (NP (NNS investigators)))) (S (VP (TO to) (VP (VB examine) (NP (PRP it))))))))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150811" id="2356543" ><text>T
Two people were killed yesterday afternoon and another seriously injured in , Sweden.  The injured man is considered a suspect in the knife attack and was arrested in hospital.  Another man was arrested at the scene, which was an  furniture retailer.  According to police, the two fatalities do not have any obvious connection to the suspects, but did know each other.  The motive is, thus far, unknown.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (S (NP (CD Two) (NNS people)) (VP (VBD were) (VP (VBN killed) (NP (NN yesterday) (NN afternoon))))) (CC and) (S (NP (DT another)) (VP (ADVP (RB seriously)) (VBN injured) (PRT (IN in)))) (, ,) (NP (NNP Sweden)) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150815" id="2359609" ><text>F
On Wednesday, -based football club  defeated -based football club  5-;4 to win the  . The match was held in  in the city of , . , who may leave for , scored the winning goal of the match in the 115th minute. This was the fifth UEFA Super cup won by Barcelona.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (PP (IN On) (NP (NNP Wednesday))) (, ,) (: -) (VP (VBN based) (NP (NN football) (S (VP (NN club) (VP (VBD defeated) (: -) (S (VP (VBN based) (VP (NN football) (NP (NN club) (CD 5) (: -) (: ;) (NP (CD 4) (S (VP (TO to) (VP (VB win) (NP (DT the))))))))))))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150812" id="2361631" ><text>R
]]A report published Wednesday by the  claims vice premier Choe Yong-gon  of North Korea was executed in May.  The report, which cites an unnamed source, has not been confirmed by Wikinews or other agencies.  The government of North Korea rarely makes statements about its internal affairs.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (NP (NP (-RRB- -RSB-) (-RRB- -RSB-) (DT A) (NN report)) (VP (VBN published) (NP (NNP Wednesday)) (PP (IN by) (NP (NP (DT the) (NNS claims) (NN vice) (NN premier) (NNP Choe) (NNP Yong-gon)) (PP (IN of) (NP (NNP North) (NNP Korea))))))) (VP (VBD was) (VP (VBN executed) (PP (IN in) (NP (NNP May))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150812" id="2361901" ><text>M
]] Malaysian officials stated Wednesday, some of the debris found in the Maldives will be brought back to Malaysia to determine if they are from Malaysia Airlines Flight 370 (MH370) as they now believe. A team arrived Tuesday in Maldives to take charge of the debris, which had previously been disposed of as trash.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (NP (-RRB- -RSB-) (-RRB- -RSB-) (JJ Malaysian) (NNS officials)) (VP (VP (VBD stated) (NP (NNP Wednesday))) (, ,) (SBAR (S (NP (NP (DT some)) (PP (IN of) (NP (NP (DT the) (NN debris)) (VP (VBN found) (PP (IN in) (NP (DT the) (NNPS Maldives))))))) (VP (MD will) (VP (VB be) (VP (VBN brought) (PRT (RB back)) (PP (TO to) (NP (NNP Malaysia))) (S (VP (TO to) (VP (VB determine) (SBAR (IN if) (S (NP (PRP they)) (VP (VBP are) (PP (IN from) (NP (NP (NNP Malaysia) (NNPS Airlines) (NNP Flight) (CD 370)) (PRN (-LRB- -LRB-) (NP (NN MH370)) (-RRB- -RRB-)))) (SBAR (IN as) (S (NP (PRP they)) (ADVP (RB now)) (VP (VBP believe)))))))))))))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150813" id="2362527" ><text>H
] ]] The Chinese news agency  reports that there have been two massive explosions within seconds of each other, at about 11:30 p.m. local time, in a warehouse in the port of Dongjiang in , a city of 15 million, near Beijing, in north-east China.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (NP (NP (-RRB- -RSB-) (-RRB- -RSB-) (-RRB- -RSB-) (NP (NP (DT The) (JJ Chinese) (NN news) (NN agency) (NNS reports)) (SBAR (WHNP (IN that)) (S (NP (EX there)) (VP (VBP have) (VP (VBN been) (NP (CD two) (JJ massive) (NNS explosions)) (PP (IN within) (NP (NP (NNS seconds)) (PP (IN of) (NP (DT each) (JJ other))))) (, ,) (PP (IN at) (PP (IN about) (NP (CD 11:30) (ADJP (RB p.m.) (JJ local)) (NN time)))) (, ,) (PP (IN in) (NP (NP (DT a) (NN warehouse)) (PP (IN in) (NP (NP (DT the) (NN port)) (PP (IN of) (NP (NNP Dongjiang))))))) (VP (IN in) (, ,) (NP (NP (DT a) (NN city)) (PP (IN of) (NP (QP (CD 15) (CD million)))) (, ,) (PP (IN near) (NP (NNP Beijing))) (, ,) (PP (IN in) (NP (NN north-east) (NNP China))))))))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150813" id="2364843" ><text>M
Debris believed to be part of an aircraft has washed ashore on an uninhabited island in the Maldives. The fragment, suspected to be from a wing, was found on Mendhoo island, within the . The finding comes after several pieces of suspected plane debris washed ashore on the resort island Vabbinfaru, within the , some of which could be from Malaysia Airlines Flight 370 (MH370).</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (S (NP (NNP Debris)) (VP (VBD believed) (S (VP (TO to) (VP (VB be) (NP (NP (NN part)) (PP (IN of) (NP (DT an) (NN aircraft)))))))) (VP (VBZ has) (VP (VBN washed) (ADVP (RB ashore)) (PP (IN on) (NP (NP (DT an) (JJ uninhabited) (NN island)) (PP (IN in) (NP (DT the) (NNPS Maldives)))))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150814" id="2366251" ><text>M
According to the Malaysian transport ministry today, investigators sent to Maldives to examine suspected plane debris say "most" of the debris recovered from several Maldives islands are unrelated to Malaysia Airlines Flight 370 (MH370) and aren't part of an aircraft.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (PP (VBG According) (PP (TO to) (NP (DT the) (JJ Malaysian) (NN transport) (NN ministry)))) (NP (NN today)) (, ,) (NP (NNS investigators)) (VP (VP (VBD sent) (PP (TO to) (NP (NNPS Maldives))) (S (VP (TO to) (VP (VB examine) (NP (VBN suspected) (NN plane) (NN debris))))) (VP (VBP say) (`` ``) (S (NP (NP (RBS most)) ('' '') (PP (IN of) (NP (NP (DT the) (NN debris)) (VP (VBD recovered) (PP (IN from) (NP (JJ several) (NNPS Maldives) (NNS islands))))))) (VP (VBP are) (ADJP (JJ unrelated) (PP (TO to) (NP (NP (NNP Malaysia) (NNP Airlines) (NNP Flight) (CD 370)) (PRN (-LRB- -LRB-) (NP (NN MH370)) (-RRB- -RRB-))))))))) (CC and) (VP (VBP are) (RB n't) (NP (NP (NN part)) (PP (IN of) (NP (DT an) (NN aircraft)))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150816" id="2371484" ><text>'
Via press release on Friday, Andy Martin, a perennial candidate for political office and self-proclaimed "Birther King", announced he is seeking the U.S. Republican Party's 2016 presidential nomination, his fourth bid for the White House.  In his announcement and subsequent release, Martin expresses a desire to participate in  and aligns himself with fellow Republican presidential candidate Donald Trump.  Additionally, he outlines six reasons for running, including degrading the candidacy of former Florida  Jeb Bush, who is also seeking the Republican nomination.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (NP (NP (NNP Via) (NN press) (NN release)) (PP (IN on) (NP (NNP Friday))) (, ,) (NP (NNP Andy) (NNP Martin)) (, ,) (NP (NP (DT a) (JJ perennial) (NN candidate)) (PP (IN for) (NP (NP (JJ political) (NN office)) (CC and) (NP (JJ self-proclaimed) (`` ``) (NP (NNP Birther) (NNP King)) ('' ''))))) (, ,)) (VP (VBD announced) (SBAR (S (NP (PRP he)) (VP (VBZ is) (NP (VBG seeking) (NP (NP (DT the) (NNP U.S.) (NNP Republican) (NNP Party) (POS 's)) (CD 2016) (JJ presidential) (NN nomination)) (, ,) (NP (NP (PRP$ his) (JJ fourth) (NN bid)) (PP (IN for) (NP (DT the) (NNP White) (NNP House))))))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150818" id="2372151" ><text>T
Two pieces of suspected plane debris found washed ashore  islands in the  have been taken back to  for further analysis, Malaysia announced on Sunday. The pieces were found last Friday. Investigators are trying to determine if they're connected to  (MH370).</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (NP (NP (CD Two) (NNS pieces)) (PP (IN of) (NP (VBN suspected) (NN plane) (NN debris)))) (VP (VBD found) (S (VP (VBN washed) (NP (NP (RB ashore) (NNS islands)) (PP (IN in) (NP (DT the) (VP (VBP have) (VP (VBN been) (VP (VBN taken) (ADVP (RB back) (PP (TO to) (PP (IN for) (NP (NP (JJ further) (NN analysis)) (, ,) (NP (NP (NNP Malaysia)) (VP (VBD announced) (PP (IN on) (NP (NNP Sunday)))))))))))))))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150817" id="2373669" ><text>W
]] A woman in Spain has been fined 800 after posting a photograph to her Facebook account of a police vehicle parked in space reserved for  drivers.  She was located and fined within two days of posting the photograph.  The incident has now gained international attention.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (NP (NP (-RRB- -RSB-) (-RRB- -RSB-) (DT A) (NN woman)) (PP (IN in) (NP (NNP Spain)))) (VP (VBZ has) (VP (VBN been) (VP (VBN fined) (NP (CD 800)) (PP (IN after) (S (VP (VBG posting) (NP (DT a) (NN photograph)) (PP (TO to) (NP (NP (PRP$ her) (NNP Facebook) (NN account)) (PP (IN of) (NP (NP (DT a) (NN police) (NN vehicle)) (VP (VBN parked) (PP (IN in) (NP (NN space)))))))) (VP (VBN reserved) (PP (IN for) (NP (NNS drivers)))))))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150820" id="2378969" ><text>W
Former U.S.    took some time to talk with Wikinews about his campaign for the U.S. Republican Party's 2016 presidential nomination.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (NP (JJ Former) (NNP U.S.)) (VP (VBD took) (NP (NP (DT some) (NN time)) (SBAR (S (VP (TO to) (VP (VB talk) (PP (IN with) (NP (NNP Wikinews))) (PP (IN about) (NP (NP (PRP$ his) (NN campaign)) (PP (IN for) (NP (NP (DT the) (NNP U.S.) (NNP Republican) (NNP Party) (POS 's)) (CD 2016) (JJ presidential) (NN nomination))))))))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150820" id="2383692" ><text>P
A protest was held ahead of the start of the fifth  cricket  today, seeking a higher standard of cricket administration. ] Around 100 protesters, which included writer ,  editor , and ,  for , gathered outside the  cricket ground to observe three minutes of silence, a minute for each of the "Big Three" nations - India, England, and Australia. Organisers claim these nations of controlling cricket's governance to benefit themselves.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (NP (DT A) (NN protest)) (VP (VBD was) (VP (VBN held) (ADVP (RB ahead) (PP (IN of) (NP (NP (DT the) (NN start)) (PP (IN of) (NP (NP (DT the) (JJ fifth) (NN cricket)) (NP (NN today))))))) (, ,) (S (VP (VBG seeking) (NP (NP (DT a) (JJR higher) (NN standard)) (PP (IN of) (NP (NN cricket) (NN administration)))))))) (. .) (-RRB- -RSB-)))</parse><sentence date="20150820" id="2383919" ><text>P
Two planes carrying parachutists collided this morning in western Slovakia, near the Czech Republic. Of around 40 on board, seven are confirmed dead.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (NP (NP (CD Two) (NNS planes)) (VP (VBG carrying) (NP (NNS parachutists)))) (VP (VBD collided) (NP (DT this) (NN morning)) (PP (IN in) (NP (JJ western) (NNP Slovakia))) (, ,) (PP (IN near) (NP (DT the) (NNP Czech) (NNP Republic)))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150821" id="2384888" ><text>C
Stars from the world of showbusiness joined fans and mourners yesterday at the funeral of the popular entertainer . Her coffin was transported in a cortege in  where she grew up, with hundreds of people paying their respects. Some were holding memorabilia related to Black's 50-year long career in entertainment, which included singing and presenting television programmes such as .</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (NP (NP (NNP Stars)) (PP (IN from) (NP (NP (DT the) (NN world)) (PP (IN of) (NP (NN showbusiness)))))) (VP (VBD joined) (NP (NP (NNS fans)) (CC and) (NP (NNS mourners))) (NP (NN yesterday)) (PP (IN at) (NP (NP (DT the) (NN funeral)) (PP (IN of) (NP (DT the) (JJ popular) (NN entertainer)))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150821" id="2385032" ><text>N
According to  news agency, quoting 's main news agency  (KCNA), the country's military has been placed on high alert and has been told to prepare a "quasi-state of war". The report comes after North and  exchanged artillery fire yesterday.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (NP (NP (PP (VBG According) (PP (TO to) (NP (NN news) (NN agency)))) (, ,) (NP (NP (NP (NP (VBG quoting) (POS 's)) (JJ main) (NN news) (NN agency)) (PRN (-LRB- -LRB-) (NP (NN KCNA)) (-RRB- -RRB-))) (, ,) (S (NP (NP (DT the) (NN country) (POS 's)) (NN military)) (VP (VP (VBZ has) (VP (VBN been) (VP (VBN placed) (PP (IN on) (ADJP (JJ high) (JJ alert)))))) (CC and) (VP (VBZ has) (VP (VBN been) (VP (VBN told) (S (VP (TO to) (VP (VB prepare) (NP (NP (DT a) (`` ``) (NN quasi-state)) (PP (IN of) (NP (NN war)))))))))))) ('' ''))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150822" id="2386647" ><text>'
]]  A gunman yesterday wounded three people on an international train in Belgium, near the French border. Belgian Prime Minister  called the shooting a "terrorist attack" and French counterterrorism police are investigating.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (NP (-RRB- -RSB-) (-RRB- -RSB-) (DT A) (NN gunman)) (NP (NN yesterday)) (VP (VBD wounded) (NP (CD three) (NNS people)) (PP (IN on) (NP (NP (DT an) (JJ international) (NN train)) (PP (IN in) (NP (NNP Belgium))))) (, ,) (PP (IN near) (NP (DT the) (JJ French) (NN border)))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150823" id="2389235" ><text>V
] Police warn more bodies may remain to be found after yesterday's crash of a vintage jet killed at least seven people. The  crashed into a busy road during the  in England.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (SBAR (-RRB- -RSB-) (S (NP (NNP Police)) (VP (VB warn) (NP (JJR more) (NNS bodies))))) (VP (MD may) (VP (VB remain) (S (VP (TO to) (VP (VB be) (VP (VBN found) (PP (IN after) (NP (NP (NP (NN yesterday) (POS 's)) (NN crash)) (PP (IN of) (NP (NP (DT a) (JJ vintage) (NN jet)) (VP (VBN killed) (NP (QP (IN at) (JJS least) (CD seven)) (NNS people))))))))))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150823" id="2389384" ><text>A
A midair collision today killed a pilot during an airshow in the village of  in Switzerland.  The crash occurred as three  planes from the German Grasshopper display team flew together in formation. Two collided and crashed, with one pilot ejecting and parachuting to safety and the other remaining on board and being killed. The third plane was not directly involved and landed successfully.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (NP (DT A) (JJ midair) (NN collision)) (NP (NN today)) (VP (VBD killed) (NP (DT a) (NN pilot)) (PP (IN during) (NP (NP (DT an) (NN airshow)) (PP (IN in) (NP (NP (DT the) (NN village)) (PP (IN of) (PP (IN in) (NP (NNP Switzerland))))))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150825" id="2390599" ><text>I
]]</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (INTJ (-RRB- -RSB-) (-RRB- -RSB-)))</parse><sentence date="20150825" id="2394485" ><text>U
In a judgement released today Mr Justice Green, sitting in the  in London, spoke of his "very considerable unease" as he rejected an application by two defendants in a Thai death penalty case. The pair sought a Metropolitan Police report they hoped could assist their defence.  The court has expedited the case. Burmese nationals Zaw Lin and Wai Phyo, both 22, are currently on trial accused of murdering David Miller, 24, from Jersey, and Hannah Witheridge, 23, from England. With the defence case due to begin shortly and continue until mid- or late September the court has issued its judgement today following a hearing on Friday.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (PP (IN In) (NP (NP (DT a) (NN judgement)) (VP (VBN released) (NP (NN today) (NNP Mr) (NNP Justice) (NNP Green)) (, ,) (S (VP (VBG sitting) (PP (IN in) (NP (NP (DT the)) (PP (IN in) (NP (NNP London)))))))))) (, ,) (VP (VBD spoke) (PP (IN of) (NP (PRP$ his) (`` ``) (RB very) (JJ considerable) (NN unease) ('' ''))) (SBAR (IN as) (S (NP (PRP he)) (VP (VBD rejected) (NP (DT an) (NN application)) (PP (IN by) (NP (NP (CD two) (NNS defendants)) (PP (IN in) (NP (DT a) (NNP Thai) (NN death) (NN penalty) (NN case))))))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150826" id="2396448" ><text>G
Yesterday in Guatemala, the  approved the attorney general's request to impeach President . ]] The final decision on lifting Presidential immunity now falls to . The case relates to a corruption scandal known locally as  which has seen Vice President  arrested and charged with fraud and receiving bribes. Prosecutors allege Baldetti and Molina between them received half of all bribes in the case.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (NP (NP (NP (NN Yesterday)) (PP (IN in) (NP (NNP Guatemala)))) (, ,) (NP (DT the) (VBN approved) (NP (NP (DT the) (NN attorney) (NN general) (POS 's)) (NN request) (S (VP (TO to) (VP (VB impeach) (NP (NNP President))))))) (. .) (-RRB- -RSB-) (-RRB- -RSB-)))</parse><sentence date="20150826" id="2397497" ><text>V
Two members of a news crew for , Virginia station  were shot and killed on live television this morning. The suspect, a former reporter for the news station, later shot himself after a manhunt of several hours, authorities said.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (NP (NP (CD Two) (NNS members)) (PP (IN of) (S (NP (DT a) (NN news) (NN crew)) (IN for) (, ,) (NP (NNP Virginia) (NN station)) (VP (VBD were) (VP (VBN shot) (CC and) (VP (VBN killed) (PP (IN on) (NP (JJ live) (NN television))) (NP (DT this) (NN morning))))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150828" id="2398134" ><text>G
Parts of the Indian state of Gujarat have been under curfew since Tuesday. At least seven are reported dead, with over 100 buses and dozens of police stations burned, after protests over job quotas turned violent in several major cities including , , and .  The violence is thought to have started after a brief attempt by police to arrest protest leader Hardik Patel, 22 or 21. There have been weeks of protests by members of the  caste, with the most recent involving an estimated half a million people.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (NP (NP (NNS Parts)) (PP (IN of) (NP (NP (DT the) (JJ Indian) (NN state)) (PP (IN of) (NP (NNP Gujarat)))))) (VP (VBP have) (VP (VBN been) (PP (IN under) (NP (NN curfew))) (PP (IN since) (NP (NNP Tuesday))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150827" id="2398612" ><text>A
]]  Austrian police today found an estimated 20-;50 decomposing corpses in an apparently abandoned lorry.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (NP (-RRB- -RSB-) (-RRB- -RSB-) (JJ Austrian) (NNS police)) (NP (NN today)) (VP (VBD found) (NP (NP (DT an) (VBN estimated) (CD 20)) (: -) (: ;) (NP (NP (CD 50) (VBG decomposing) (NNS corpses)) (PP (IN in) (NP (DT an) (ADJP (RB apparently) (VBN abandoned)) (NN lorry)))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150827" id="2398767" ><text>S
, the President of South Sudan, yesterday signed a deal designed to end a civil ethnic conflict that has killed thousands and displaced over two million.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (X (, ,) (NP (NP (NP (DT the) (NNP President)) (PP (IN of) (NP (NNP South) (NNP Sudan)))) (, ,) (S (NP (NN yesterday)) (VP (VBD signed) (NP (NP (DT a) (NN deal)) (VP (VBN designed) (S (VP (TO to) (VP (VB end) (NP (NP (DT a) (JJ civil) (JJ ethnic) (NN conflict)) (SBAR (WHNP (WDT that)) (S (VP (VP (VBZ has) (VP (VBN killed) (NP (NNS thousands)))) (CC and) (VP (VBD displaced) (PP (IN over) (NP (CD two) (CD million)))))))))))))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150830" id="2402563" ><text>C
Al Jazeera journalists Canadian , Egyptian Baher Mohamed, and Australian  were sentenced yesterday to three years in prison by judge Hassan Farid following a retrial of the 2013 case in Cairo.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (NP (NP (NNP Al) (NNP Jazeera) (NNS journalists) (JJ Canadian)) (, ,) (NP (JJ Egyptian) (NNP Baher) (NNP Mohamed)) (, ,) (CC and) (NP (JJ Australian))) (VP (VBD were) (VP (VBN sentenced) (NP (NN yesterday)) (PP (TO to) (NP (NP (NP (CD three) (NNS years)) (PP (IN in) (NP (NN prison)))) (PP (IN by) (NP (NN judge) (NNP Hassan) (NNP Farid))))) (PP (VBG following) (NP (NP (DT a) (NN retrial)) (PP (IN of) (NP (NP (DT the) (CD 2013) (NN case)) (PP (IN in) (NP (NNP Cairo))))))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150829" id="2402675" ><text>F
Four foreign men have today gone before a court in Hungary on suspicion of people smuggling. Their detention relates to Thursday's discovery of a lorry full of corpses in Austria. The death toll was yesterday finalised at 71. ]] The lorry had been abandoned since Wednesday on the  of the "", near the Hungarian border. Roadworkers became suspicious of dark liquid seeping from the vehicle, and responding police found the bodies. Initial police estimates were that 20-;50 were suffocated in the back of the lorry which was near .</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (NP (CD Four) (JJ foreign) (NNS men)) (VP (VBP have) (NP (NN today)) (VP (VBN gone) (PP (IN before) (NP (NP (DT a) (NN court)) (PP (IN in) (NP (NNP Hungary))))) (PP (IN on) (NP (NP (NN suspicion)) (PP (IN of) (NP (NNS people) (NN smuggling))))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150831" id="2406229" ><text>F
A fire in the eastern Saudi city of  tore through a housing complex for oil workers yesterday, killing eleven, according to civil officials. ] The Radium complex is rented by oil firm  for their employees. According to nearby resident Mohammed Siddique the fire broke out early in the morning. Siddique says the building contains locals, as well as Westerners and Asians. The cause is unclear but the civil defence ministry tweeted "Cars and furniture caught fire in the basement of one of the towers".</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (FRAG (FRAG (NP (NP (DT A) (NN fire)) (PP (IN in) (NP (NP (DT the) (JJ eastern) (JJ Saudi) (NN city)) (PP (IN of) (S (VP (VBN tore) (PP (IN through) (NP (NP (DT a) (NN housing) (NN complex)) (PP (IN for) (NP (NN oil) (NNS workers))))) (NP (NN yesterday)) (, ,) (NP (NP (VBG killing) (NNS eleven)) (, ,) (PP (VBG according) (PP (TO to) (NP (JJ civil) (NNS officials))))))))))) (. .)) (-RRB- -RSB-)))</parse><sentence date="20150903" id="2408168" ><text>D
Queensland, Australia on Tuesday opened a specialist court dedicated to dealing with  cases. The  Court on the  is to undergo a six-month trial, after which domestic violence courts may be opened across the rest of the state. The court's motto is "timeliness, access and resolution"; it aims to see domestic violence cases lodged and heard on the same day.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (NP (NP (NP (NNP Queensland)) (, ,) (NP (NP (NNP Australia)) (PP (IN on) (NP (NNP Tuesday)))) (VP (VBD opened) (NP (NP (DT a) (NN specialist) (NN court)) (VP (VBN dedicated) (PP (TO to) (S (VP (VBG dealing) (PP (IN with) (NP (NNS cases)))))))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150901" id="2408472" ><text>B
]] Nick Bos, of the , studies "the amazing adaptations social insects have evolved in order to fight the extreme parasite pressure they experience". In a recently-accepted  paper Bos and colleagues describe ants appearing to self-medicate.  The team used , an ant species that can form thousand-strong colonies. This common black ant eats other insects, and also . It often nests in tree stumps or under rocks and foraging workers can sometimes be spotted climbing trees.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (FRAG (NP (NP (-RRB- -RSB-) (-RRB- -RSB-) (NNP Nick) (NNP Bos)) (, ,) (PP (IN of) (NP (DT the) (, ,) (NNS studies))) (`` ``) (NP (NP (DT the) (JJ amazing) (NNS adaptations)) (SBAR (S (NP (JJ social) (NNS insects)) (VP (VBP have) (VP (VBN evolved) (SBAR (IN in) (NN order) (S (VP (TO to) (VP (VB fight) (NP (NP (DT the) (JJ extreme) (NN parasite) (NN pressure)) (SBAR (S (NP (PRP they)) (VP (VBP experience)))))))))))))) ('' '')) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150903" id="2413050" ><text>S
A study published yesterday by  estimates the global tree population at just over three trillion. Previous work estimated the total at 400 billion. ] The international research, led by Yale University in the US, used satellite images to examine over 400,000 plots of land for estimated tree density. Subarctic regions of , Russia, and North America had the highest densities but the largest forested areas were tropical. The study puts 43% of trees in the tropics, where deforestation is particularly common.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (NP (DT A) (NN study)) (VP (VBN published) (NP (NN yesterday)) (PP (IN by) (NP (NP (NNS estimates)) (NP (DT the) (JJ global) (NN tree) (NN population)))) (PP (IN at) (NP (QP (RB just) (IN over) (CD three) (CD trillion))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150904" id="2414520" ><text>D
Yesterday the Dutch Defence Ministry said a Dutch sergeant, whose identity was not disclosed, may have gone to Syria from the Netherlands because he wanted to join extremist militant group ISIS. Prosecutors are investigating the sergeant.  Jeanie Hennis Plasschaer, Dutch Defence Minister, called the act of leaving one's country to join ISIS "irresponsible" and "punishable". "Every case of radicalisation is one too many. It is disappointing if it appears that someone joins evil while colleagues risk their lives for the freedom of another."</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (NP (NN Yesterday)) (NP (DT the) (NNPS Dutch) (NNP Defence) (NNP Ministry)) (VP (VBD said) (SBAR (S (NP (NP (DT a) (JJ Dutch) (NN sergeant)) (, ,) (SBAR (WHNP (WP$ whose) (NN identity)) (S (VP (VBD was) (RB not) (VP (VBN disclosed))))) (, ,)) (VP (MD may) (VP (VB have) (VP (VBN gone) (PP (TO to) (NP (NNP Syria))) (PP (IN from) (NP (DT the) (NNP Netherlands))) (SBAR (IN because) (S (NP (PRP he)) (VP (VBD wanted) (S (VP (TO to) (VP (VB join) (NP (NN extremist) (JJ militant) (NN group) (NNP ISIS)))))))))))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150907" id="2416425" ><text>U
The US economy added 173,000 jobs in August, the  reported on Friday. The unemployment rate fell from 5.3 to 5.1 percent, the lowest since April 2008.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (X (S (NP (DT The) (NNP US) (NN economy)) (VP (VBD added) (NP (CD 173,000) (NNS jobs)) (PP (IN in) (NP (NNP August))))) (, ,) (NP (NP (DT the) (VBN reported)) (PP (IN on) (NP (NNP Friday)))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150909" id="2426493" ><text>R
The Rwandan  today agreed to hear a case opposing a  amendment allowing President Paul Kagame to run for a third term. ]] The government attorney had asked the court to throw the case, brought by the opposition , out. An eight-judge panel rejected that move. Kagame has grown popular at home and abroad following  reconstruction but the constitution does not allow a third term.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (NP (NP (NP (DT The) (JJ Rwandan)) (NP (NP (NN today)) (VP (VBD agreed) (S (VP (TO to) (VP (VB hear) (S (NP (DT a) (NN case)) (VP (VBG opposing) (NP (NP (DT a) (NN amendment)) (VP (VBG allowing) (S (NP (NNP President) (NNP Paul) (NNP Kagame)) (VP (TO to) (VP (VB run) (PP (IN for) (NP (DT a) (JJ third) (NN term))))))))) (. .) (-RRB- -RSB-)))))))) (NP (-RRB- -RSB-))))</parse><sentence date="20150910" id="2427869" ><text>I
The US federal National Transportation Safety Board (NTSB) yesterday concluded a "series of errors" by flight crew caused a  crash near Boston, Massachusetts last year. Seven were killed when the  overran a runway.  The NTSB found the pilots failed to conduct preflight checks, mistakenly took off with flight control systems locked in position, and then failed to abort takeoff until too late. Manufacturer  was criticised for an inadequate safety system; the US Federal Aviation Administration (FAA) was accused of failing to properly check the system before certifying the aircraft.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (NP (NP (NP (NP (DT The) (NNP US) (JJ federal) (NNP National) (NNP Transportation) (NNP Safety) (NNP Board)) (PRN (-LRB- -LRB-) (NP (NNP NTSB)) (-RRB- -RRB-))) (SBAR (S (NP (NP (NN yesterday)) (VP (VBD concluded) (NP (NP (DT a) (`` ``) (NN series)) (PP (IN of) (NP (NNS errors)))) ('' '') (PP (IN by) (NP (NN flight) (NN crew))))) (VP (VBD caused) (NP (NP (DT a) (NN crash)) (PP (IN near) (NP (NNP Boston))))))) (, ,) (NP (NNP Massachusetts) (JJ last) (NN year))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150911" id="2429916" ><text>T
Radioactive water has been leaking from the damaged Fukushima nuclear plant following damage caused by . The plant's drainage system has been inundated by a surge of sea water brought in by the typhoon, which reached Japan on Wednesday. A spokesperson for TEPCO, the company that runs the plant, yesterday said they were investigating the leaked water but it did not present a significant danger.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (NP (JJ Radioactive) (NN water)) (VP (VBZ has) (VP (VBN been) (VP (VBG leaking) (PP (IN from) (NP (DT the) (VBN damaged) (NP (NNP Fukushima) (JJ nuclear) (NN plant)))) (PP (VBG following) (NP (NP (NN damage)) (VP (VBN caused) (PP (IN by)))))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150914" id="2436308" ><text>A
The federal party room of the  has voted to change its leader this evening local time (). Malcolm Turnbull has been elected over incumbent Prime Minister Tony Abbott 54 votes to 44.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (NP (NP (DT The) (JJ federal) (NN party) (NN room)) (PP (IN of) (NP (DT the)))) (VP (VBZ has) (VP (VBN voted) (S (VP (TO to) (VP (VB change) (NP (PRP$ its) (NN leader)) (NP (NP (DT this) (NN evening) (JJ local) (NN time)) (PRN (-LRB- -LRB-) (-RRB- -RRB-)))))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150916" id="2441108" ><text>K
A court in Kuwait yesterday sentenced fifteen people for involvement in June's bombing of the Imam Sadiq Mosque. Seven were sentenced to death.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (NP (NP (NP (DT A) (NN court)) (PP (IN in) (NP (NNP Kuwait))) (NP (NP (NN yesterday)) (VP (VBN sentenced) (NP (CD fifteen) (NNS people)) (PP (IN for) (NP (NP (NN involvement)) (PP (IN in) (NP (NP (NP (NNP June) (POS 's)) (NN bombing)) (PP (IN of) (NP (DT the) (NNP Imam) (NNP Sadiq) (NNP Mosque)))))))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150916" id="2441316" ><text>S
Fifty years after starting his first sandwich shop as a teenager,  CEO and co-founder  died on Monday. He was 67 and suffering from cancer. ] Subway yesterday announced his death, but not the location. He had developed , which the company announced in 2013. The business was founded with friend Peter Buck who lent DeLuca 1,000 to open Pete's Super Submarines in , Connecticut. The company remains based in the state.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (FRAG (NP (NP (CD Fifty) (NNS years)) (PP (IN after) (S (VP (VBG starting) (NP (PRP$ his) (JJ first) (NN sandwich) (NN shop)) (SBAR (IN as) (S (NP (NP (DT a) (NN teenager)) (, ,) (NP (NNP CEO)) (CC and) (NP (NN co-founder))) (VP (VBD died) (PP (IN on) (NP (NNP Monday)))))))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150917" id="2443845" ><text>S
An overturned tanker exploded in , South Sudan yesterday, killing dozens. ]] The death toll is unclear. At least 85 died according to presidential spokesman Ateny Wek Ateny, citing "local authorities". Charles Kisagna of the local government said at least 100 died. County commissioner Wilson Thomas Yanga in remarks to the BBC put the toll at a minimum of 176.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (SINV (NP (DT An) (VBN overturned) (NN tanker)) (VBD exploded) (IN in) (, ,) (S (VP (NP (NNP South) (NNP Sudan)) (NP (NN yesterday)) (, ,) (S (VP (VBG killing) (NP (NNS dozens))))) (. .) (PRN (-RRB- -RSB-) (-RRB- -RSB-)))))</parse><sentence date="20150917" id="2443938" ><text>R
Romanian Prime Minister Victor Ponta was today indicted for fraud offences.  The move follows a previous charging, which sees Ponta accused of forgery, , , and having a conflict of interest. He is set to become the nation's first Prime Minister to face trial while in power.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (NP (JJ Romanian) (NNP Prime) (NNP Minister) (NNP Victor) (NNP Ponta)) (VP (VBD was) (NP (NP (NN today)) (VP (VBN indicted) (PP (IN for) (NP (NN fraud) (NNS offences)))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150918" id="2445671" ><text>L
Mr Justice Saunders today imprisoned a man for eight years at the  in London after an FBI sting in which he tried to buy  on the .  Mohammed Ali, 31, from Liverpool, was convicted at trial of attempting to possess a chemical weapon. He told the jury he was "curious" about the Dark Web, which is a largely hidden and difficult to police section of the Internet. Ali said he didn't realise he had done anything illegal.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (NP (NNP Mr) (NNP Justice) (NNP Saunders)) (NP (NN today)) (VP (VBD imprisoned) (NP (DT a) (NN man)) (PP (IN for) (NP (CD eight) (NNS years))) (PP (IN at) (NP (NP (DT the)) (PP (IN in) (NP (NNP London))))) (PP (IN after) (NP (NP (DT an) (NNP FBI) (NN sting)) (SBAR (WHPP (IN in) (WHNP (WDT which))) (S (NP (PRP he)) (VP (VBD tried) (S (VP (TO to) (VP (VB buy) (PP (IN on) (NP (DT the)))))))))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150926" id="2454042" ><text>C
The week-long  in Burkina Faso ended on Wednesday with the restoration of interim President  and the civilian government. By yesterday the government announced that the presidential guard unit involved in the coup, the , would be dissolved.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (NP (NP (DT The) (JJ week-long)) (PP (IN in) (NP (NP (NNP Burkina) (NNP Faso)) (VP (VBD ended) (PP (IN on) (NP (NNP Wednesday))) (PP (IN with) (NP (NP (NP (DT the) (NN restoration)) (PP (IN of) (NP (JJ interim) (NNP President)))) (CC and) (NP (DT the) (JJ civilian) (NN government))))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20150927" id="2465939" ><text>I
Regional elections are taking place today in , , in which the biggest talking point is whether the  should become an independent country. The polls are being held early as the national government has not allowed an official referendum on independence. Opinion polls, according to , suggest the secessionists will win more than half of the 135  seats but less than half of the popular vote.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (NP (NNP Regional) (NNS elections)) (VP (VBP are) (VP (VBG taking) (NP (NN place)) (NP (NN today)) (UCP (IN in) (, ,) (, ,) (SBAR (WHPP (IN in) (WHNP (WDT which))) (S (NP (DT the) (JJS biggest) (NN talking) (NN point)) (VP (VBZ is) (SBAR (IN whether) (S (DT the) (VP (MD should) (VP (VB become) (NP (DT an) (JJ independent) (NN country)))))))))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20151001" id="2468551" ><text>N
]/(TEMPLATE)]  On Monday, NASA announced that signs of liquid water have been found on Mars. The  spacecraft found evidence of the liquid on the Martian surface, in long dark spots on the Red Planet thought to be formed because of water flow.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (-RRB- -RSB-) (: /) (PRN (-LRB- -LRB-) (NP (NN TEMPLATE)) (-RRB- -RRB-)) (-RRB- -RSB-) (PP (IN On) (NP (NNP Monday))) (, ,) (NP (NNP NASA)) (VP (VBD announced) (SBAR (IN that) (S (NP (NP (NNS signs)) (PP (IN of) (NP (JJ liquid) (NN water)))) (VP (VBP have) (VP (VBN been) (VP (VBN found) (PP (IN on) (NP (NNP Mars))))))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20151001" id="2474158" ><text>R
Russian jets stationed reportedly in the Syrian city of  have been carrying out air strikes since yesterday, in support of Syrian President Bashar al-Assad, having notified the United States an hour before.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (NP (JJ Russian) (NNS jets)) (VP (VBN stationed) (ADVP (RB reportedly)) (PP (IN in) (NP (NP (DT the) (JJ Syrian) (NN city)) (PP (IN of) (S (VP (VBP have) (VP (VBN been) (VP (VBG carrying) (PRT (RP out)) (NP (NN air) (NNS strikes)) (PP (IN since) (NP (NN yesterday)))))))))) (, ,) (PP (IN in) (NP (NP (NN support)) (PP (IN of) (NP (JJ Syrian) (NNP President) (NNP Bashar) (NNP al-Assad))))) (, ,) (S (VP (VBG having) (VP (VBN notified) (NP (DT the) (NNP United) (NNPS States)) (VP (NP (DT an) (NN hour)) (PP (IN before))))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20151004" id="2477399" ><text>S
Nine people were killed on Thursday by 26-year-old Chris Harper Mercer on the campus of  in , Oregon. By various reports seven or nine people were also injured. Officials said Mercer killed himself during the subsequent shootout with police.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (NP (CD Nine) (NNS people)) (VP (VBD were) (VP (VBN killed) (PP (IN on) (NP (NNP Thursday))) (PP (IN by) (NP (NP (JJ 26-year-old) (NNP Chris) (NNP Harper) (NNP Mercer)) (PP (IN on) (NP (NP (DT the) (NN campus)) (PP (IN of) (NP (IN in) (, ,) (NNP Oregon))))))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20151006" id="2483801" ><text>C
], [[File:Kunduz MSF Trauma Center - location map - 01.png, 190px, center, thumb, The location of the hospital in Kunduz. (TEMPLATE)]]] Twenty two civilians, including three children, died,  (MSF) reported, on Saturday after a United States airstrike hit a hospital in the city of  in northern Afghanistan. Amongst the fatalities were twelve charity staff working for MSF. MSF said there were about two hundred people in the building.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (FRAG (-RRB- -RSB-) (, ,) (PRN (-LRB- -LSB-) (-LRB- -LSB-) (NP (NP (NNP File)) (: :) (NP (NP (NP (NNP Kunduz) (NNP MSF) (NNP Trauma) (NNP Center) (: -) (NN location) (NN map) (: -) (NN 01.png)) (, ,) (NP (NP (NN 190px)) (, ,) (NP (NN center)) (, ,) (NP (NN thumb)) (, ,))) (NP (NP (DT The) (NN location)) (PP (IN of) (NP (DT the) (NN hospital))) (PP (IN in) (NP (NNP Kunduz))))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20151008" id="2487108" ><text>B
United States Presidential candidate Bernie Sanders discussed his understanding of the  on Monday.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (NP (NNP United) (NNPS States) (JJ Presidential) (NN candidate) (NNP Bernie) (NNP Sanders)) (VP (VBD discussed) (NP (NP (PRP$ his) (NN understanding)) (PP (IN of) (NP (DT the)))) (PP (IN on) (NP (NNP Monday)))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20151008" id="2492371" ><text>T
Yesterday, , permanent secretary of the , announced this year's Nobel Prize in Chemistry is awarded to three scientists for their work on .</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (NP (NP (NP (NN Yesterday)) (, ,) (, ,) (JJ permanent) (NN secretary)) (PP (IN of) (NP (DT the))) (, ,) (VP (VBD announced) (SBAR (S (NP (NP (NP (DT this) (NN year) (POS 's)) (NNP Nobel) (NNP Prize)) (PP (IN in) (NP (NNP Chemistry)))) (VP (VBZ is) (VP (VBN awarded) (PP (TO to) (NP (NP (CD three) (NNS scientists)) (PP (IN for) (NP (NP (PRP$ their) (NN work)) (PP (IN on))))))))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20151009" id="2493652" ><text>A
NASA released yesterday the first coloured pictures of Pluto's blue atmosphere and water ice on the surface taken by the space probe New Horizons.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (NP (NNP NASA)) (VP (VBD released) (NP (NN yesterday)) (NP (NP (DT the) (JJ first) (VBN coloured) (NNS pictures)) (PP (IN of) (NP (NP (NP (NNP Pluto) (POS 's)) (JJ blue) (NN atmosphere)) (CC and) (NP (NN water) (NN ice)))) (PP (IN on) (NP (NP (DT the) (NN surface)) (VP (VBN taken) (PP (IN by) (NP (DT the) (NN space) (NN probe) (NNP New) (NNP Horizons)))))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20151009" id="2493859" ><text>T
Three top FIFA (International Federation of Association Football) officials have been suspended from their jobs yesterday for a period of ninety days pending an internal inquiry into alleged corruption. The three are FIFA President Sepp Blatter, Vice President  and Secretary General . They aren't allowed to participate in football-related activities during their suspensions.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (NP (NP (CD Three) (JJ top) (NNP FIFA)) (PRN (-LRB- -LRB-) (NP (NP (NNP International) (NNP Federation)) (PP (IN of) (NP (NNP Association) (NNP Football)))) (-RRB- -RRB-))) (NP (NNS officials)) (VP (VBP have) (VP (VBN been) (VP (VBN suspended) (PP (IN from) (NP (PRP$ their) (NNS jobs))) (NP (NN yesterday)) (PP (IN for) (NP (NP (NP (DT a) (NN period)) (PP (IN of) (NP (CD ninety) (NNS days)))) (PP (VBG pending) (NP (NP (DT an) (JJ internal) (NN inquiry)) (PP (IN into) (NP (JJ alleged) (NN corruption)))))))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20151010" id="2494060" ><text>J
Liverpool-based football club  (LFC) appointed German  as the club's new manager. Klopp signed a three-year contract with LFC for 15 million, with annual earnings of ¬£5 million and an increment to ¬£7 million if the club wins the  or if the club qualifies for the .</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (NP (NP (JJ Liverpool-based) (NN football) (NN club) (-LRB- -LRB-) (NN LFC) (-RRB- -RRB-) (JJ appointed) (JJ German)) (PP (IN as) (NP (NP (DT the) (NN club) (POS 's)) (JJ new) (NN manager))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20151013" id="2504968" ><text>I
Today, two Israelis were reported killed and several injured as a result of an attack on a bus in Jerusalem. This is one of several violent occurrences from today, as part of a recent surge of violence in the region.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (NP (NN Today)) (, ,) (S (S (NP (CD two) (NNPS Israelis)) (VP (VBD were) (VP (VBN reported) (S (VP (VBN killed)))))) (CC and) (S (NP (JJ several)) (VP (VBN injured) (PP (IN as) (NP (NP (DT a) (NN result)) (PP (IN of) (NP (NP (DT an) (NN attack)) (PP (IN on) (NP (NP (DT a) (NN bus)) (PP (IN in) (NP (NNP Jerusalem)))))))))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20151014" id="2505571" ><text>N
Yesterday, the  football team crashed out of the   after a 2-;3 defeat against the  in . Dutch player  scored an own goal.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (NP (NN Yesterday)) (, ,) (NP (DT the) (NN football) (NN team)) (VP (VBD crashed) (PP (IN out) (PP (IN of) (NP (DT the)))) (PP (IN after) (NP (NP (DT a) (LST (LS 2) (: -)) (: ;) (CD 3) (NN defeat)) (PP (IN against) (NP (DT the) (NN in)))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20151015" id="2506784" ><text>S
The  in  yesterday said a nurse suffering with complications after Ebola, Pauline Cafferkey, is "critically ill" after her condition deteriorated. Cafferkey, 39, was readmitted to an isolation unit at the Royal Free on the night of October 8-;9 where she had spent time earlier in the year after contracting Ebola in  whilst treating patients with the infection.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (NP (DT The) (PP (IN in) (NP (NN yesterday)))) (VP (VBD said) (SBAR (S (NP (NP (NP (DT a) (NN nurse) (NN suffering)) (PP (IN with) (NP (NNS complications))) (PP (IN after) (NP (NNP Ebola)))) (, ,) (NP (NNP Pauline) (NNP Cafferkey)) (, ,)) (VP (VBZ is) (`` ``) (ADJP (RB critically) (JJ ill)) ('' '') (SBAR (IN after) (S (NP (PRP$ her) (NN condition)) (VP (VBN deteriorated)))))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20151017" id="2512907" ><text>P
have closed down an , Alberta, Canada pizza restaurant for a single day for delivering  despite not being licensed to do so. It is unclear when this incident occurred, but the CBC reported that it occurred "recently", after police searched the shop in September.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (VP (VB have) (VP (VBN closed) (ADVP (RB down) (NP (DT an) (, ,) (NNP Alberta) (, ,) (NNP Canada) (NN pizza) (NN restaurant))) (PP (IN for) (NP (DT a) (JJ single) (NN day))) (PP (IN for) (S (VP (VBG delivering) (PP (IN despite) (S (VP (RB not) (VBG being) (VP (VBN licensed) (S (VP (TO to) (VP (VB do) (ADVP (RB so)))))))))))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20151019" id="2514064" ><text>R
Portuguese footballer  surpassed 's goal scoring record for Spanish club Real Madrid in a La Liga match against  on Saturday. Ronaldo netted his 324th goal in his 310th match for Los Blancos on Saturday, breaking the  previous record set by Spanish footballer Ra√∫l of 323 goals in 741 games.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (NP (JJ Portuguese) (NN footballer)) (VP (VBD surpassed) (VP (POS 's) (NP (NP (NN goal)) (VP (VBG scoring) (NP (NN record)) (PP (IN for) (NP (JJ Spanish) (NN club) (JJ Real) (NNP Madrid))) (PP (IN in) (NP (NP (DT a) (NNP La) (NNP Liga) (NN match)) (PP (IN against) (PP (IN on) (NP (NNP Saturday)))))))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20151019" id="2516838" ><text>S
] Searchers looking for New Zealand fishing boat FV Jubilee found the vessel on the sea floor overnight local time ().</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (-RRB- -RSB-) (NP (NP (NNPS Searchers)) (VP (VBG looking) (PP (IN for) (NP (NNP New) (NNP Zealand) (NN fishing) (NN boat) (NN FV) (NN Jubilee))))) (VP (VBD found) (NP (NP (DT the) (NN vessel)) (PP (IN on) (NP (NP (DT the) (NP (NN sea) (NN floor) (JJ overnight) (JJ local) (NN time))) (PRN (-LRB- -LRB-) (-RRB- -RRB-)))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20151019" id="2516970" ><text>T
, known additionally as Lando, made landfall in the northern Philippines on Sunday, killing at least two and displacing at least 16,000 people.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (, ,) (S (VP (VBN known) (ADVP (RB additionally)) (PP (IN as) (NP (NNP Lando))))) (, ,) (VP (VBD made) (NP (NN landfall)) (PP (IN in) (NP (NP (DT the) (JJ northern) (NNPS Philippines)) (PP (IN on) (NP (NNP Sunday))))) (, ,) (S (VP (VBG killing) (NP (QP (IN at) (JJS least) (CD two)) (ADJP (NP (CC and))) (S (VP (VBG displacing) (NP (QP (IN at) (JJS least) (CD 16,000)) (NNS people)))))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20151021" id="2520008" ><text>I
Indian cricketer  yesterday announced his retirement from  and the next  season.  Sehwag played his last  in March 2013 against . He scored 8,586 runs, including 23 , in 104 test matches, with a  of 49.34.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (NP (JJ Indian) (NN cricketer)) (NP (NN yesterday)) (VP (VBD announced) (NP (NP (NP (PRP$ his) (NN retirement)) (PP (IN from))) (CC and) (NP (DT the) (JJ next) (NN season)))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20151020" id="2520381" ><text>L
A London man charged on Sunday with drugging and murdering four men made his first court appearance yesterday. Stephen Port, 40, was remanded to appear before a higher court tomorrow. ]] Port faces four counts of murder and four counts of "administering a poison with intent to endanger life or inflict ". He is alleged to have administered overdoses of recreational drug . He allegedly murdered the men at his home before dumping the bodies, after finding victims online using  dating services.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (NP (NP (DT A) (NNP London) (NN man)) (VP (VP (VBN charged) (PP (IN on) (NP (NNP Sunday))) (PP (IN with) (NP (NN drugging)))) (CC and) (VP (VBG murdering) (NP (CD four) (NNS men))))) (VP (VBD made) (NP (PRP$ his) (JJ first) (NN court) (NN appearance)) (NP (NN yesterday))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20151022" id="2526406" ><text>F
, an Austrian woman who won the 2013  crown, died early this week in hospital. She was 26 and fell whilst jogging in the Austrian  on Friday.  Kadiƒá fell roughly 30 down the  mountain in , near  where she worked. She was taken to  with injuries to her head, pelvis, and lung. Remaining conscious after the fall, she had alerted her family via telephone who in turn contacted emergency services.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (, ,) (NP (NP (DT an) (JJ Austrian) (NN woman)) (SBAR (WHNP (WP who)) (S (VP (VBD won) (NP (DT the) (CD 2013) (NN crown)))))) (, ,) (VP (VBD died) (NP (RB early) (DT this) (NN week)) (PP (IN in) (NP (NN hospital)))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20151023" id="2527020" ><text>M
A masked man killed a teacher and an 11 year old student in a sword attack at a school in  yesterday, before police who arrived at the scene fatally shot him.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (NP (DT A) (VBN masked) (NN man)) (VP (VP (VBD killed) (NP (DT a) (NN teacher))) (CC and) (NP (NP (DT an) (CD 11) (NN year) (JJ old) (NN student)) (PP (IN in) (NP (NP (DT a) (NN sword) (NN attack)) (PP (IN at) (NP (NP (DT a) (NN school)) (PP (IN in) (NP (NN yesterday)))))))) (, ,) (SBAR (IN before) (S (NP (NP (NNS police)) (SBAR (WHNP (WP who)) (S (VP (VBD arrived) (PP (IN at) (NP (DT the) (NN scene))))))) (ADVP (RB fatally)) (VP (VBD shot) (NP (PRP him)))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20151027" id="2535767" ><text>M
Early yesterday afternoon local time, a 7.5 magnitude earthquake hit Afghanistan, Pakistan and , with its  in the  mountain range which stretches from Afghanistan to North Pakistan, causing damage to life and buildings. A Wikinews correspondent felt the shock waves in , Rajasthan at 2:50 PM  (0920 ).</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (NP (NP (RB Early) (NN yesterday) (NN afternoon) (JJ local) (NN time)) (, ,) (S (NP (DT a) (CD 7.5) (NN magnitude) (NN earthquake)) (VP (VBD hit) (NP (NNP Afghanistan)))) (, ,) (NP (NNP Pakistan)) (CC and) (, ,) (PP (IN with) (NP (PRP$ its) (PP (IN in) (NP (NP (DT the) (NN mountain) (NN range)) (SBAR (WHNP (WDT which)) (S (VP (VBZ stretches) (PP (IN from) (NP (NNP Afghanistan))) (PP (TO to) (NP (NNP North) (NNP Pakistan))) (, ,) (S (VP (VBG causing) (NP (NP (NN damage)) (PP (TO to) (NP (NN life) (CC and) (NNS buildings))))))))))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20151031" id="2546044" ><text>R
Officials said at least 27 people are dead and 155 injured after  effects used at the Colectiv  in Bucharest, Romania reportedly malfunctioned yesterday, sparking a fire.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (NP (NNS Officials)) (VP (VBD said) (SBAR (S (SBAR (S (S (NP (QP (IN at) (JJS least) (CD 27)) (NNS people)) (VP (VBP are) (ADJP (JJ dead)))) (CC and) (S (NP (CD 155)) (VP (VBN injured) (SBAR (IN after) (S (NP (NNS effects)) (VP (VBN used) (PP (IN at) (NP (NP (DT the) (NNP Colectiv)) (PP (IN in) (NP (NNP Bucharest)))))))))))) (, ,) (NP (NNP Romania)) (ADVP (RB reportedly)) (VP (VBD malfunctioned) (NP (NN yesterday)) (, ,) (S (VP (VBG sparking) (NP (DT a) (NN fire)))))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20151104" id="2555307" ><text>V
]] The Volkswagen emissions scandal continued yesterday with the company announcing 800,000 mainly diesel vehicles may also be affected by  emissions problems.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (NP (NP (-RRB- -RSB-) (-RRB- -RSB-) (NP (DT The) (NN Volkswagen) (NNS emissions) (NN scandal))) (VP (VBD continued) (NP (NN yesterday)) (PP (IN with) (NP (NP (DT the) (NN company)) (VP (VBG announcing) (NP (CD 800,000) (ADJP (RB mainly) (JJ diesel)) (NNS vehicles))))))) (VP (MD may) (ADVP (RB also)) (VP (VB be) (VP (VBN affected) (PP (IN by) (NP (NNS emissions) (NNS problems)))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20151111" id="2573121" ><text>M
, President of the Maldives, yesterday lifted the state of emergency he imposed on his nation last week. ] Attorney General  cited progress in an investigation into the bombing of Yameen's speedboat in September. The state of emergency was imposed last Wednesday with Yameen reporting security concerns.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (FRAG (, ,) (NP (NP (NP (NNP President)) (PP (IN of) (NP (DT the) (NNPS Maldives)))) (, ,) (NP (NN yesterday)) (VP (VBD lifted) (NP (NP (NP (DT the) (NN state)) (PP (IN of) (NP (NN emergency)))) (SBAR (S (NP (PRP he)) (VP (VBD imposed) (PP (IN on) (NP (PRP$ his) (NN nation))) (NP (JJ last) (NN week)))))))) (. .) (-RRB- -RSB-)))</parse><sentence date="20151112" id="2575168" ><text>S
A judge in Pretoria, South Africa yesterday sentenced eight police officers to fifteen years' imprisonment each for the 2013 murder of . Mozambican immigrant Macia was dragged behind a police van and beaten in what the judge called a "barbaric" attack. ] Judge Bert Bam rejected the 25-year maximum sentence, citing a lack of premeditation and the otherwise good records of the officers involved. Judge Bam said he could not be more lenient owing to a lack of remorse.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (NP (NP (DT A) (NN judge)) (PP (IN in) (NP (NP (NNP Pretoria)) (, ,) (NP (NNP South) (NNP Africa)) (NP (NN yesterday))))) (VP (VBN sentenced) (NP (CD eight) (NNS police) (NNS officers)) (PP (TO to) (NP (NP (NP (NP (CD fifteen) (NNS years) (POS ')) (NN imprisonment)) (NP (DT each))) (PP (IN for) (NP (NP (DT the) (CD 2013) (NN murder)) (PP (IN of))))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20151114" id="2580067" ><text>N
driver Nico Rosberg today took pole position for tomorrow's 2015  at , making it his fifth pole in a row. Lewis Hamilton was second fastest. Four-time world champion  rounded up the top three.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (NP (NN driver) (NNP Nico) (NNP Rosberg) (NN today)) (VP (VBD took) (NP (NN pole) (NN position)) (PP (IN for) (NP (NP (NN tomorrow) (POS 's)) (ADVP (CD 2015) (IN at)))) (, ,) (S (VP (VBG making) (S (NP (PRP it)) (NP (NP (PRP$ his) (JJ fifth) (NN pole)) (PP (IN in) (NP (DT a) (NN row)))))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20151117" id="2586790" ><text>R
The  of Rwanda today voted to amend the  to allow a third term for President Paul Kagame. ]] The changes, which require a referendum before becoming law, reduce the current limit of two seven-year Presidential terms to two five-year terms. Kagame receives an exemption allowing another seven-year term before starting to count his five-year terms. If approved the amendments can keep him in power until 2034.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (NP (NAC (DT The) (PP (IN of) (NP (NNP Rwanda)))) (NP (NN today))) (VP (VBD voted) (S (VP (TO to) (VP (VB amend) (NP (DT the) (S (VP (TO to) (VP (VB allow) (NP (NP (DT a) (JJ third) (NN term)) (PP (IN for) (NP (NNP President) (NNP Paul) (NNP Kagame))))))))))) (. .) (-RRB- -RSB-)) (-RRB- -RSB-)))</parse><sentence date="20151120" id="2591007" ><text>G
Feminist author and academic  gave a lecture at Cardiff University on Wednesday despite a petition with over 3,000 signatures calling for its cancellation.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (NP (NP (NNP Feminist) (NN author)) (CC and) (NP (JJ academic))) (VP (VBD gave) (NP (NP (DT a) (NN lecture)) (PP (IN at) (NP (NNP Cardiff) (NNP University)))) (PP (IN on) (NP (NNP Wednesday))) (PP (IN despite) (NP (NP (DT a) (NN petition)) (PP (IN with) (NP (QP (IN over) (CD 3,000)) (NNS signatures))) (VP (VBG calling) (PP (IN for) (NP (PRP$ its) (NN cancellation))))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20151122" id="2594623" ><text>A
] Australian  was named on Friday as 's new rugby union head coach by the  (RFU), making him the first foreign coach to be appointed to the role. Jones has signed a four year contract after  resigned from the post in early November following England's disappointing performance at this year's .</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (NP (-RRB- -RSB-) (SBAR (S (NP (NNP Australian)) (VP (VBD was) (VP (VBN named) (PP (IN on) (NP (NNP Friday))) (PP (IN as) (NP (NP (POS 's) (JJ new) (JJ rugby) (NN union) (NN head) (NN coach)) (PP (IN by) (NP (DT the) (PRN (-LRB- -LRB-) (NP (NN RFU)) (-RRB- -RRB-)))))) (, ,) (S (VP (VBG making) (S (NP (PRP him)) (NP (NP (DT the) (JJ first) (JJ foreign) (NN coach)) (SBAR (S (VP (TO to) (VP (VB be) (VP (VBN appointed) (PP (TO to) (NP (DT the) (NN role)))))))))))))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20151121" id="2595745" ><text>S
A court in Saudi Arabia sentenced Saudi-born Palestinian poet  to death on Tuesday for allegedly committing , a crime punishable by death under Saudi Arabia's  of . The court decision was brought to light yesterday by Adam Coogle, a researcher working for .</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (FRAG (NP (NP (DT A) (NN court)) (PP (IN in) (NP (NP (NNP Saudi) (NNP Arabia)) (VP (VBN sentenced) (NP (JJ Saudi-born) (JJ Palestinian) (NN poet)) (PP (TO to) (NP (NN death))) (PP (IN on) (NP (NNP Tuesday))) (PP (IN for) (UCP (S (ADVP (RB allegedly)) (VP (VBG committing))) (, ,) (NP (NP (DT a) (NN crime)) (ADJP (JJ punishable) (PP (IN by) (NP (NN death))) (PP (IN under) (NP (NP (NNP Saudi) (NNP Arabia) (POS 's)) (PP (IN of)))))))))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20151123" id="2597390" ><text>B
On Saturday,  based  club  defeated their arch rivals  4-;0 at  in  in a Spanish  match.   Bar√ßa had greater ball possession. The match saw five  and one . Three Madrid players were yellow carded with a total of 23 fouls committed in the match.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (PP (IN On) (NP (NNP Saturday))) (, ,) (NP (VBN based) (NN club)) (VP (VBD defeated) (NP (PRP$ their) (JJ arch) (NNS rivals)) (VP (LST (LS 4) (: -)) (PRN (: ;) (CD 0) (PP (IN at) (PP (IN in) (PP (IN in) (NP (DT a) (JJ Spanish) (NN match)))))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20151125" id="2604142" ><text>P
Marium Mukhtiar yesterday became the first Pakistani female fighter pilot to die on duty when a jet aircraft crashed near , in Punjab's  district. ] The  (PAF) said Flying Officer Mukhtiar and male colleague Squadron Leader Saqib Abbasi faced a "serious in-flight emergency" while training in an  fighter. After taking evasive action to avoid a residential area the pilots were left with insufficient altitude to safely eject. Both ejected and were injured; Mukhtiar died in hospital whilst Abbasi sustained minor injuries.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (NP (NNP Marium) (NNP Mukhtiar)) (NP (NN yesterday)) (VP (VBD became) (NP (NP (DT the) (JJ first) (JJ Pakistani) (NN female) (NN fighter) (NN pilot)) (SBAR (S (VP (TO to) (VP (VB die) (PP (IN on) (NP (NN duty))) (SBAR (WHADVP (WRB when)) (S (NP (DT a) (NN jet) (NN aircraft)) (VP (VBD crashed) (ADVP (RB near)) (, ,) (PP (IN in) (NP (NP (NNP Punjab) (POS 's)) (NN district)))))))))))) (. .) (-RRB- -RSB-)))</parse><sentence date="20151124" id="2604410" ><text>F
] , a ferry in service in Fiji, capsized and sank in  Harbour today.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (NP (NP (-RRB- -RSB-) (, ,) (NP (NP (DT a) (NN ferry)) (PP (IN in) (NP (NP (NN service)) (PP (IN in) (NP (NP (NNP Fiji)) (, ,) (NP (VBN capsized)) (CC and) (VP (VBN sank) (PP (IN in) (NP (NNP Harbour))) (NP (NN today))))))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20151125" id="2606509" ><text>A
A bombing outside the  in central Athens, Greece early yesterday morning caused heavy damage to the Cypriot embassy across the street. ]] The explosion hit Xenofontos Street around 3.30 a.m.  (0130 ). Police had cordoned off the area after two local newspapers received calls warning of the impending blast 30-;40 minutes before the blast. Unconfirmed reports state the bomb as being 3 of explosives left in a backpack outside the office and detonated by a timer.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (PRN (S (NP (NP (DT A) (NN bombing)) (PP (IN outside) (NP (DT the) (PP (IN in) (NP (NP (JJ central) (NNP Athens)) (, ,) (NP (NP (NNP Greece)) (NP (RB early) (NN yesterday) (NN morning)))))))) (VP (VBD caused) (NP (NP (NP (JJ heavy) (NN damage)) (PP (TO to) (NP (DT the) (NNP Cypriot) (NN embassy)))) (PP (IN across) (NP (DT the) (NN street))))) (. .) (-RRB- -RSB-)) (-RRB- -RSB-)))</parse><sentence date="20151126" id="2607102" ><text>N
The Law and Justice Party of Poland, which took power last week, this week removed web pages featuring the results of an investigation into the  in Russia in 2010. The cause of the crash, which killed Polish President , is disputed.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (NP (NP (DT The) (NN Law)) (CC and) (NP (NP (NNP Justice) (NNP Party)) (PP (IN of) (NP (NNP Poland)))) (, ,) (SBAR (WHNP (WDT which)) (S (VP (VBD took) (NP (NN power)) (NP (JJ last) (NN week))))) (, ,)) (NP (DT this) (NN week)) (VP (VBD removed) (NP (NP (NN web) (NNS pages)) (VP (VBG featuring) (NP (NP (DT the) (NNS results)) (PP (IN of) (NP (NP (DT an) (NN investigation)) (PP (IN into) (NP (DT the) (PP (IN in) (NP (NP (NNP Russia)) (PP (IN in) (NP (CD 2010))))))))))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20151202" id="2623481" ><text>I
Indonesia's National Transportation Safety Committee yesterday declared pilot error to be behind the crash of Indonesia AirAsia Flight 8501. All 162 passengers and crew died when the plane crashed into the Java Sea a year ago. ]] The  was around 40 minutes from Surabaya's  to Singapore's  when it vanished on December 28. Wreckage and bodies were found floating two days later; National Search and Rescue Agency divers led an international recovery effort but over 50 bodies remain lost.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (NP (NP (NNP Indonesia) (POS 's)) (NNP National) (NNP Transportation) (NNP Safety) (NNP Committee)) (NP (NN yesterday)) (VP (VBD declared) (S (NP (NN pilot) (NN error)) (VP (TO to) (VP (VB be) (PP (IN behind) (NP (NP (DT the) (NN crash)) (PP (IN of) (NP (NNP Indonesia) (NNP AirAsia) (NNP Flight) (CD 8501))))))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20151207" id="2633626" ><text>C
Yesterday, at least seven people including ,  governor  died in a car bomb attack on their convoy in the city of Aden, according to local officials. An online claim of responsibility on behalf of militant group  called Saad a "tyrant".</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (NP (NN Yesterday)) (, ,) (NP (QP (IN at) (JJS least) (CD seven)) (NNS people)) (VBG including) (, ,) (NP (NN governor)) (VP (VBD died) (PP (IN in) (NP (NP (DT a) (NN car) (NN bomb) (NN attack)) (PP (IN on) (NP (PRP$ their) (NN convoy))) (PP (IN in) (NP (NP (DT the) (NN city)) (PP (IN of) (NP (NNP Aden))))))) (, ,) (PP (VBG according) (PP (TO to) (NP (JJ local) (NNS officials))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20151208" id="2634914" ><text>U
A UK court has remanded a man in custody after he appeared in court over a stabbing incident in the capital London. Muhaydin Mire, a 29-year-old from east London, was charged with attempted murder after reportedly at least two people were injured, one seriously, in  on Saturday. The suspect, who spoke only to confirm personal details in yesterday's hearing at , is also set to appear at the  on Friday.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (NP (DT A) (NNP UK) (NN court)) (VP (VBZ has) (VP (VBN remanded) (NP (NP (DT a) (NN man)) (PP (IN in) (NP (NN custody)))) (SBAR (IN after) (S (NP (PRP he)) (VP (VBD appeared) (PP (IN in) (NP (NN court))) (PP (IN over) (NP (DT a) (VBG stabbing) (NN incident))) (PP (IN in) (NP (DT the) (NN capital) (NNP London)))))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20151209" id="2640205" ><text>P
A petition reached over 300,000 signatures today urging Donald Trump, considered the front runner to become the 's candidate for President of the , be banned from entering the . This follows Mr Trump's comments that  should be blocked from entering the US.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (NP (DT A) (NN petition)) (VP (VBD reached) (PP (IN over) (NP (CD 300,000) (NNS signatures))) (S (NP (NN today)) (VP (VBG urging) (NP (NNP Donald) (NNP Trump)) (, ,) (VP (VBD considered) (S (NP (DT the) (JJ front) (NN runner))) (S (VP (TO to) (VP (VB become) (NP (NP (NP (DT the) (POS 's)) (NN candidate)) (PP (IN for) (NP (NP (NNP President)) (PP (IN of) (NP (DT the)))))))))) (, ,) (VP (VB be) (VP (VBN banned) (PP (IN from) (S (VP (VBG entering) (NP (DT the)))))))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20151212" id="2641167" ><text>U
On Wednesday, English football club  defeated Greek  3-;0 in a  group stage match played at , .</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (PP (IN On) (NP (NNP Wednesday))) (, ,) (NP (NNP English) (NN football) (NN club)) (VP (VBD defeated) (SBAR (S (JJ Greek) (LST (LS 3) (: -)) (: ;) (CD 0) (VP (PP (IN in) (NP (DT a) (NN group) (NN stage) (NN match))) (VBD played) (PP (IN at)) (, ,))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20151212" id="2642549" ><text>U
On Wednesday, German football club Bayern Munich defeated Croatian football club  in a  group stage match played , .</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (PP (IN On) (NP (NNP Wednesday))) (, ,) (NP (NNP German) (NN football) (NN club) (NNP Bayern) (NNP Munich)) (VP (VBD defeated) (NP (JJ Croatian) (NN football) (NN club)) (PP (IN in) (NP (DT a) (NN group) (NN stage) (NN match)))) (VP (VBD played)) (, ,) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20151213" id="2645930" ><text>W
, New York Councilman Steve Burke took some time to speak with Wikinews about his campaign for the U.S. Democratic Party's 2016 presidential nomination.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (, ,) (NP (NNP New) (NNP York) (NNP Councilman) (NNP Steve) (NNP Burke)) (VP (VBD took) (NP (DT some) (NN time)) (S (VP (TO to) (VP (VB speak) (PP (IN with) (NP (NNP Wikinews))) (PP (IN about) (NP (NP (PRP$ his) (NN campaign)) (PP (IN for) (NP (NP (DT the) (NNP U.S.) (NNP Democratic) (NNP Party) (POS 's)) (CD 2016) (JJ presidential) (NN nomination))))))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20151212" id="2647577" ><text>U
A petition on the  government's website, calling for  Presidential hopeful  to be barred from entering the country, has now passed a half-million signatories becoming the most-popular petition ever posted on the site. The signatories include a majority of UK .</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (NP (NP (DT A) (NN petition)) (PP (IN on) (NP (NP (DT the) (NN government) (POS 's)) (NN website))) (, ,) (VP (VBG calling) (PP (IN for) (NP (JJ Presidential) (ADJP (JJ hopeful) (S (VP (TO to) (VP (VB be) (VP (VBN barred) (PP (IN from) (S (VP (VBG entering) (NP (DT the) (NN country))))))))))))) (, ,)) (VP (VBZ has) (ADVP (RB now)) (VP (VBN passed) (NP (NP (DT a) (NN half-million) (NNS signatories)) (VP (VBG becoming) (SBAR (S (NP (DT the) (JJ most-popular) (NN petition)) (ADVP (RB ever)) (VP (VBD posted) (PP (IN on) (NP (DT the) (NN site)))))))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20151214" id="2647809" ><text>U
On Saturday evening, the  draw took place at the  in ; UEFA Euro 2016 is scheduled to be hosted in France. 24 nations were drawn in six groups, with the host nation placed in Group A. The quadrennial football tournament of Europe is scheduled to start in June 2016, the matches to be played in ten French cities.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (S (PP (IN On) (NP (NNP Saturday) (NN evening))) (, ,) (NP (DT the) (NN draw)) (VP (VBD took) (NP (NN place)) (PP (IN at) (NP (DT the) (NN in))))) (: ;) (S (NP (NNP UEFA) (NNP Euro) (CD 2016)) (VP (VBZ is) (VP (VBN scheduled) (S (VP (TO to) (VP (VB be) (VP (VBN hosted) (PP (IN in) (NP (NNP France)))))))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20151216" id="2651790" ><text>U
On Monday, the draw for the Last 16 for the  took place in , Switzerland at 12:00 . The draw took place in two pots, one consisting of the respective group winners, and the second of the runners-up.  Winners of the Last 16 play in the quarter-finals.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (X (PP (IN On) (NP (NNP Monday))) (, ,) (NP (NP (DT the) (NN draw)) (PP (IN for) (NP (DT the) (JJ Last) (CD 16))) (PP (IN for) (NP (DT the) (VBD took) (NN place))) (FRAG (IN in) (, ,) (NP (NP (NNP Switzerland)) (PP (IN at) (NP (CD 12:00)))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20151218" id="2661124" ><text>S
Yesterday, Catalonia-based football club FC Barcelona defeated Chinese  3-;0 at  in  in a  semifinal match hosted in Japan.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (FRAG (NP (NN Yesterday)) (, ,) (NP (NP (JJ Catalonia-based) (NN football) (NN club) (NN FC)) (SBAR (S (NP (NNP Barcelona)) (VP (VBD defeated) (NP (JJ Chinese) (LST (LS 3) (: -)) (: ;) (NP (CD 0) (PP (IN at) (PP (IN in) (PP (IN in) (NP (NP (DT a) (JJ semifinal) (NN match)) (VP (VBN hosted) (PP (IN in) (NP (NNP Japan)))))))))))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20151217" id="2661618" ><text>C
Today, -based football club Chelsea F.C. sacked Jos√© Mourinho from the position of the club's manager.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (NP (NN Today)) (, ,) (: -) (NP (VBN based) (NN football) (NN club) (NNP Chelsea) (NNP F.C.)) (VP (VBD sacked) (NP (NN Jos√) (CD ©) (NNP Mourinho)) (PP (IN from) (NP (NP (DT the) (NN position)) (PP (IN of) (NP (NP (DT the) (NN club) (POS 's)) (NN manager)))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20151220" id="2669496" ><text>B
Today, Catalonia-based football club FC Barcelona defeated Argentine club  FC 3-;0 at  in  in the  final hosted in Japan.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (NP (NN Today)) (PRN (, ,) (NP (NP (JJ Catalonia-based) (NN football) (NN club) (NN FC)) (SBAR (S (NP (NNP Barcelona)) (VP (VBD defeated) (NP (JJ Argentine) (NN club) (NN FC) (CD 3)))))) (: -)) (: ;) (VP (CD 0) (PP (IN at) (PP (IN in) (PP (IN in) (NP (DT the) (ADJP (JJ final) (S (VP (VBN hosted) (PP (IN in) (NP (NNP Japan))))))))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20151220" id="2669969" ><text>C
Today, -based football club  defeated  3-;2 at  in  in the  final.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (NP (NN Today)) (, ,) (: -) (NP (VBN based) (NN football) (NN club)) (VP (VBD defeated) (VP (LST (LS 3) (: -)) (PRN (: ;) (CD 2) (PP (IN at) (PP (IN in) (PP (IN in) (NP (DT the) (JJ final)))))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20151221" id="2669993" ><text>A
Munich-based football club Bayern Munich yesterday announced their current manager  would remain only to this season's end. Former Real Madrid manager  would replace the Spaniard next season.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (NP (JJ Munich-based) (NN football) (NN club) (NNP Bayern) (NNP Munich)) (NP (NN yesterday)) (VP (VBD announced) (SBAR (S (NP (PRP$ their) (JJ current) (NN manager)) (VP (MD would) (VP (VB remain) (PP (ADVP (RB only)) (TO to) (NP (NP (DT this) (NN season) (POS 's)) (NN end)))))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20151222" id="2670669" ><text>S
On Sunday, Slovenians voted on a referendum to legalize same-sex marriage. The referendum failed to pass, with opposing majority.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (PP (IN On) (NP (NNP Sunday))) (, ,) (NP (NNP Slovenians)) (VP (VBD voted) (PP (IN on) (NP (DT a) (NN referendum))) (S (VP (TO to) (VP (VB legalize) (NP (JJ same-sex) (NN marriage)))))) (. .)))</parse><sentence date="20151223" id="2673380" ><text>S
On Monday, a suicide bomber blew himself up on a motorcycle in , . The bombing killed six   service members and injured several others.</text></sentence><parse>(ROOT (S (PP (IN On) (NP (NNP Monday))) (, ,) (NP (DT a) (NN suicide) (NN bomber)) (VP (VBD blew) (NP (PRP himself)) (PRT (RP up)) (PP (IN on) (NP (NP (DT a) (NN motorcycle)) (PP (IN in) (, ,))))) (. .)))</parse></sentences>